[MUSIC]
(音乐)
Stanford University, Welcome to Stanford CS193P,
斯坦福大学,欢迎来到斯坦福CS193P
this is Developing Applications for iOS,
这是iOS应用程序开发,
winter of 2017, This is the only lecture in this quarter
2017年冬天,这是唯一的在这个季度讲座
where I'm not going to do a demo, so this is all slides,
我不会做一个演示,这是所有幻灯片,
and that's because I'm pretty much going to try and
因为我要尝试
get you fully up to speed on Swift, Everything that I'm
让你完全速度迅速,我的一切
going to talk about today is covered either in your reading
今天要讲的是覆盖在你的阅读
assignment one, which was due today, so hopefully you're
分配一个,今天到期,所以希望你
done with that, or it's in reading assignment two,
完成了,或者是在阅读作业2
which is going out today and is due next Wednesday, So,
今天外出,预计下星期三,所以,
why am I even covering this? Because I know that reading
为什么我甚至覆盖吗?
through that reading assignment can be a big slog
通过阅读作业可以是一个很大的跋涉
through a lot of information, and I want you to understand
通过大量的信息,我希望你能理解
the things in there that are really important, As I go
那里的东西很重要,我走了
through the slides today, if you see something and
通过今天的幻灯片,如果你看到的东西
I explain it and you're like, my gosh I didn't get that,
我解释一下,你喜欢,我的天啊我没有得到,
just make a note about whatever the topic is that I'm
只是记下不管主题是我
talking about and then you can go back and
然后你可以回去
read about it again in your reading assignment to try and
读过一遍阅读作业来
understand it, If you still don't understand it,
理解,如果你还是不明白,
you can of course ask on the class forums,
你当然可以问类论坛,
You can think of this as kind of the highlights of the fist
你可以认为这是一种突出的拳头
two reading assignments, Some of these are also highlights
两个阅读作业,其中一些也突出了
of the first two lectures I did in the demos,
前两节课我做演示,
so there's a little bit of that in there to,
有一点,在那里,
But, this is really kind of the important stuff in Swift,
但是,这真的是很重要的东西在迅速,
that I can teach you at this point,
我可以教你,
There's more important stuff in Swift to come, okay,
在斯威夫特有更重要的东西,好吧,
but I'll teaching it kinda as we go in the next two weeks,
但我会教它有点像我们在接下来的两周,
Okay, so lot of Swift topics,
好的,所以很多迅速的话题,
let's start with the first one, probably everybody's
让我们从第一个开始,可能每个人的
favorite topic when they first learn Swift,
最喜欢的话题当他们第一次学习迅速,
which is optional, Optional is interesting in Swift,
这是可选的,在迅速、可选的很有趣
because not a lot of other languages have optional, so
因为不是很多其他语言可选的,所以
I'm sure, in fact I've heard, that some of you are like,
我相信,事实上我听说,你们中有些人就像,
"Hmm, I'm not sure I really understand that optional
“嗯,我不确定我真的明白,可选的
thing", And that's probably okay, but by the end of next
事”,这可能是好的,但明年年底
week you should feel very confident with Optionals,
周与可选的你应该感到非常有信心,
because you're gonna see that they are absolutely everywhere
因为你会看到,他们绝对是无处不在
in iOS, Now, I mentioned this in the lecture but
在iOS,讲座,但现在,我提到这个
I wanted to show it to you from a code,
我想展示给你一个代码,
kind of a code point of view, which is that optional
一种代码的角度来看,这是可选的
is nothing more than an enum, it is fact just an enum,
只不过是一个枚举,它实际上只是一个枚举,
this is the enum that is an optional, It's a generic type,
这是一个可选的枚举,这是一个泛型类型,
kind of like array, how with array when you say the type,
有点像数组,数组类型当你说,如何
you say the type of the thing you're putting in the array,
你说的类型将数组中,
You should all be familiar to that, with that from Java for
你应该熟悉,从Java
example, same thing in Swift,
例子中,斯威夫特一样,
So, with optional it is the same way,
可选的是同样的方式,
you put this type and the type that's associated there, or
你把这类型和类型的关联,或
not that's associated, but
不相关的,但
the type of the generic type that we're talking about,
泛型类型的类型,我们讨论,
that "T" in an optional,
在一个可选的“T”,
is just the type that's going to be the associated value,
只是一个类型就是相关的值,
When you look at this enum Optional,
当你看这个枚举可选的,
it only has two cases: "none" which is "not set," and
它只有两种情况:“没有”“不是,”
"some" which is "set", When it's in the some case, look:
“一些”,这是“集”,当它在一些情况下,看:
"(T)", you know what that is from the calculator demo,
”(T)
that's an associated value, just like when we had
这是一个关联的值,就像当我们
operation in calculator it had associated values, like unary
在计算器操作相关的值,就像一元
operation had an associative value of a function, and
操作有一个关联的价值功能,
constant had an associated value of the constant's value,
不断有一个相关值常数的值,
Same thing here, with optional, in the "some" case,
这里也一样,可选的,在“一些”的情况下,
the "set" case, it just has an associated value, and
“套”的情况下,它有一个相关值
it's whatever type the option was, so
这是任何类型的选项,所以
if this is an optional string, then it would be a string,
如果这是一个可选的字符串,那么这将是一个字符串,
Now what makes optional like, " I don't really get optional,
现在是可选的,比如“我其实真的没有什么可选的,
what is it?", it's because of all those question marks and
它是什么?
exclamation points, But, all those question marks and
感叹号,但是,所有这些问号
exclamation points, are just sugar,
感叹号,是糖,
syntactic sugar, to make your code look a little simpler and
语法糖,使代码看起来有点简单,
straight forward, because it's so common to use them, So,
笔直向前,因为它是如此常见的使用它们,所以,
I'm going to map this enum to that sugar,
我要地图这个枚举,糖,
Let's take a look, here's the first one: If I say let x:
让我们来看看,这是第一个:如果我说让x:
String?=nil, that's exactly the same as
字符串?
saying let x = Optional,none,
说让x =可选,没有,
just like by saying array, I'd say
就像说数组,我想说
Array that would mean I want an array of String,
数组那将意味着我要一个字符串数组,
here when I say Optional , that means I want
当我说选,这意味着我想要的
an Optional String, And I'm picking the none case, and
一个可选的字符串,我挑选的情况下,没有一个
in just the same way, if I say let x = Optional=
同样的,如果我说让x =可选 =
hello, I'm just saying x = Optional,some
你好,我只是说x =可选,一些
with associated value hello, Everyone got that? That's all
与关联值你好,大家都明白了吗?
that's happening there with the question mark thing,
有问号的事情发生,
And then here is the unwrap, When we do that exclamation
然后这是打开,当我们感叹
point all we're doing is doing the switch to get things out
点我们正在做的是把事情做开关
of an optional, so we're switching on the optional,
一个可选的,所以我们打开可选,
and it's in the "Some" case, then we're going to grab that
“一些”的情况,然后我们会抓住
associated value just like we did in the calculator, and
关联值计算器,就像我们所做的那样
we say "let function" or "let value" to grab the associated
我们说“让函数”或“价值”相关
value, we're saying "let value" here and
价值,我们在这里说“我们的价值”
it's grabbing that value that's associated with it,
抓,与之相关的价值,
If it's in case none, where it's not set,
如果它没有,它不是,
then it raises an exception and crashes your program,
然后提出了程序异常和崩溃,
we haven't talked about how to do that, it's quite easy, but
我们还没有谈到如何做到这一点,它很简单,但是
that's what happens here,
这里发生了什么,
that's all exclamation point is, it's basically a switch,
这就是感叹号,它基本上是一个开关,
And then finally, If we do the "if let",
最后,如果我们做“如果让”,
"if let" is also just a switch, but
“如果让”也只是一个开关,但是
in the none case of an if let, we don't raise an exception,
如果我们在没有的情况下,我们不引发异常,
we just break, break out of the switch, do nothing, Okay,
我们只是打破,打破的开关,什么也不做,好吧,
does that help you a little bit understand what optional
这帮助你一点点明白可选吗
is? Optional is a type, it's an enum, it's just like any
是什么?
other type, it just has this interesting behavior, and
其他类型,它有这个有趣的行为,
it's got all the question marks and
它有所有的问号
exclamation points to make all the code look a little
感叹号的所有代码看起来有点
simpler, Now, there's even other stuff about optionals
简单,现在,甚至还有其他东西可选
that are interesting, Optionals can be chained,
有趣的,可选的链接,
Now what does this mean? Well, this is best shown by example,
现在这是什么意思?
So, let's say I have a Optional UILabel like my
假设我有一个可选的UILabel喜欢我
display in the calculator and it's got the text, that's also
显示在计算器的文本,这是也
an optional, Optional String, we all know that, And
一个可选的,可选的字符串,我们都知道,
let's say we want to get the hashValue which is just a var
假设我们想要的hashValue只是一个var
on string, which hashes the string, gives you some integer
字符串,散列值的字符串,给你一些整数
for it, I want to get that hashValue of what's in
,我想hashValue是什么
the display, So then I would probably do some code that
显示,所以我可能会做一些代码
looks like this, this is probably similar code to what
是这样,这可能是类似的代码
we have in our calculator where I've got my display,
我们已经在我们的计算器,我有我的显示器,
that's my IBOutlet probably that display UILabel?, and
这是我IBOutlet可能显示UILabel吗?
I'm going go do "if let" here, because I don't want to crash
我要去做“如果让”在这里,因为我不想崩溃
so I don't want to do exclamation points,
所以我不想做感叹号,
I'm going to do "if let", so I'm going to say "if let
我要做“如果让”,所以我将说“如果我们
some temporary value equals to the display" (now temp1 is
一些临时的价值等于显示”(现在temp1
the UILabel), and then I say, "if let temp2 = temp1,text",
UILabel),然后我说,“如果让temp2 = temp1,文本”,
I'm sending text to the UILabel and
我发送标签和文本
now I'm getting back a String, not an Optional String, but
现在我回到一个字符串,而不是一个可选的字符串,但是
a String, because I did "if let", then I can finally say,
一个字符串,因为我做了“如果让”,然后我可以最后说,
then "let x = temp2", which is the String,
“让x = temp2”,这是字符串,
the hashValue, Okay, this is a lot of code to have to type to
hashValue,好的,这是大量的代码类型
just get that dang hashValue, out of that UILabel's text,
只是得到党hashValue,UILabel的文本,
With optional chaining, this same code looks like this,
可选的链接,这个相同的代码是这样的,
the first line of those two lines,
两行,第一行
"If let x = display?,text?,hashValue,
“如果让x =显示?、文本? hashValue,
then do something with x", In that case of course, x will
然后做一些x”,当然,在这种情况下
be a non-optional, because I'm doing if let on it,
是一个可选的,因为如果让我做,
If I take the "if" off, and just do "let x =" all that,
如果我用“如果”,只做“让x =”,
then x will be an optional Int, Now, how is this working?
那么x是一个可选的Int,现在,这是如何工作的?
What's happening is that every time that you have one of
发生了什么是,每次你的
those question marks after an Optional, it's saying,
这些问号之后,一个可选的,它是说,
if this is in the set case, then grab it and keep on
如果这是在设定的情况下,然后抓住它并继续
going, send the next thing, If it's in the nil case, then
发送下一件事,如果它是在零的情况下,
just return nil for this whole expression, this entire line,
只是为整个表达式返回nil,整个行,
boom, it's just gonna return nil, If I'm if letting it,
繁荣,就会返回nil,如果我如果让它,
then obviously the code won't get executed,
然后显然代码不会执行,
You can do as many of these as you want in a row, and
你可以做你想做的尽可能多的这些连续
we do this all the time, this optional chaining is going to
我们这样做,这个可选的链接
be all over your code, and it makes perfect sense because
在你的代码,它意义非凡,因为
again, we're using this question mark and exclamation
再一次,我们使用这个问号和感叹
point, Here we happen to use the question mark when we're
点,在这里,我们使用问号的时候发生
accessing it versus when we're declaring it, That's what it
访问和当我们宣布它,这就是它
means to use a question mark when you're accessing it,
意味着使用一个问号,当你访问它,
it means go get it, and if it's not set,
这意味着去拿,如果不设置,
then just return nil from this whole expression,
然后从整个表达式返回nil,
it will just bail out of the whole thing,
它只会拯救整个事情,
It will never even execute hash value because we'll never
它甚至不会执行散列值,因为我们永远不会
get down to that end of it, if any of these things are nil,
到年底,如果这些东西都是零,
Another cool optional things we can do is optional
另外一个很酷的可选的我们可以做的事情是可选的
defaulting, So what if we had wanted to put a string in our
违约,所以如果我们想把一个字符串中
UI label like in our display, but we know that if that
UI标签显示的一样,但是我们知道
string is nil, we don't want to put nil in there because
字符串是零,我们不想把零因为
what'll happen to our label if we put nil in as the text?
什么会发生在我们的标签如果我们把零作为文本吗?
It'll collapse down, right, probably most of you saw that,
它会崩溃下来,可能大部分人都知道,
You have to put something in there,
你要把东西放在那里,
at least a space, So let's say that I want to do that,
至少一个空间,假设我想这样做,
I want to put space in there if it's nil, This is the code
我想把空间在那里如果是零,这是代码
that it would look like here: I'd have my string, I would
它看起来像:我有我的字符串,我会的
say if the string is not nil, then put it in the display,
说如果字符串不是零,然后把它放在显示器,
otherwise, if it is nil, put space in there, This looks
否则,如果是零,把空间,这看起来
a lot cleaner with optional defaulting, which looks like
很多清洁与可选的违约,这样子
this, display,text = s That means if s is nil, use
显示,文本=这意味着如果年代nil,使用
this other thing, It's like the default in case s is nil,
其他的事情,就像默认s是零,
We will use this all the time as well, Everybody got that?
我们将使用这个,大家都明白了吗?
Just optional defaulting, Alright, so I bring those out
只是可选的违约,好了,所以我把这些
of the optional world just to highlight them,
可选的世界只是强调他们,
because there's a lot in the reading that you're doing
因为有很多的阅读你在做什么
about optional, but these are kind of the highlights,
可选的,但这些都是亮点,
There are a couple more things actually I'll show you later,
有一些事情我将向您展示后,
but basically that's it for optionals, Alright, tuples,
但基本上这是可选的,好了,元组,
So I had you skip tuples in reading assignment one, but
所以我有你跳过元组在阅读作业,但是
you'll be reading about them in reading assignment two,
你会阅读关于他们在阅读作业两个,
What is a tuple?
一个元组是什么?
A tuple is super simple, it's just a grouping of values,
元组是超级简单,它只是一个分组的价值观,
and you can use it anywhere you're using a type, What does
你可以在任何地方使用它你使用一个类型,什么
a tuple look like? It looks like this, This var here,
一个元组的呢?
this constant, actually x, I'm setting its type to be a tuple
这个常数,实际上x,我设置其类型是一个元组
with a string and int and a w, that's its type, A tuple
字符串和整数和w,其类型,一个元组
can have any number of things in there, but realistically,
可以拥有任意数量的事情,但实际上,
we probably only have three or four, sometime only two, but
我们可能只有三四个,只有两个,但是
it can have any number, I can set x equal to parentheses,
它可以包含任意数量,我可以设置x等于括号,
those three, any value of those three types, So here,
这三个,这三个类型的任何值,这里,
I've set it to hello, 5, and 0,85,
我将它设置为你好,5和0,85,
Now I can get the values out into individual variables by
现在我可以到各个变量的值
saying let parentheses three different variable names equal
说让括号三个不同的变量名相同
x, And now it will pull out the three different values
现在x,它将退出这三个不同的值
into the three separate variables, word, number, and
到三个独立变量,单词,数字,
value, So it's kind of mirror image there,
值,所以它的镜像,
you can kinda go either, either direction,
你可以提一下,两个方向,
putting things in or out, We actually, believe it or not,
把东西或,我们实际上,信不信由你,
don't do it that way most of the time,
不这样做大多数时候,
because it is also possible to name the elements of a tuple,
因为还可以命名元素的元组,
So here, I define x, same thing, string int double, but
这里,我定义x,同样的事情,字符串int的两倍,但是
look, I've named each of them,
看,我叫他们每个人,
I called the string part w, I called the int part i, and
我叫字符串部分w,我叫int的部分
I called the double part v for some reason, Now, I still set
我叫双第五部分出于某种原因,现在,我仍然设置
it equal in exactly the same way, no difference there, But
它等于以完全相同的方式,没有区别,但是
now I don't need to pull it out into separate variables,
现在我不需要拉出来到单独的变量,
I can just say x,w and get the w, the first component of it,
我可以说x,w和w,第一个组件,
You see that? This is how we do tuples, with names,
你看到了吗?
I strongly recommend you almost always use
我强烈建议你几乎总是使用
names with tuples, It's just a little easier to read,
名字与元组,它只是一个小更容易阅读,
clearer to say what your intent is as a programmer,
明确说出你的目的是作为一个程序员,
Because those names
因为这些名字
of the parts of the tuple can have good variable names,
元组的部分可以有良好的变量名,
You're gonna see in your programming assignment number
你会看到在你的编程任务数量
2, I'm gonna have you write a function that returns a tuple,
2、我要你写一个函数,返回一个元组,
and it's going to specify the names of the parts, Now even
它将指定部件的名称,甚至现在
if you name them, like we have x with the named ones,
如果你的名字,就像我们有x命名的,
you can still do that thing where you just say, let (word,
你仍然可以做那件事,你只是说,让(词,
num, val) equal x, and it'll still pull it out into
num val)= x,它还是把它拽出来
individual ones, so naming them doesn't stop you from
个人的,所以命名它们不阻止你
pulling them out by individual variable, if you want,
把他们的个体变量,如果你想要的,
Also, in tuples, you can always put underbar for
同时,在元组,你总是可以把下划线
any of the names, like here I could say let word_ val or
任何喜欢的名字,在这里我可以说让word_ val或者
let word,_, val equal x, and then I would get word and
让单词,_,val等于x,然后我会得到消息
val into individual variables, and I would just ignore that
val成单个变量,我只会忽略这一点
middle one, Underbar in Swift always kinda means ignore
中间,下划线在斯威夫特总是有点意味着忽视
that, I'm not interested in that particular thing,
我那个东西不感兴趣,
We've already seen this with function parameters when we
我们已经看到当我们与函数参数
want to ignore the external name of a function parameter,
想要忽略外部函数的参数名称,
Alright, so using tuples that return values,
好的,那么使用返回值的元组,
like I said, you're gonna see this in the homework,
就像我说的,你会看到这个作业,
Nothing special here, It's a type like any other type, so
没什么特别的,这是一个类型和其他类型
it can be the return type of a function, So, this is how you
它可以是一个函数的返回类型,所以,这就是你
can have a function that returns multiple values,
可以有一个函数,它返回多个值,
In some languages, it's very difficult to do this,
在一些语言中,很难做到这一点,
You have to create a structure or something to return,
您必须创建一个结构或返回,
However, it's very, very, very easy in Swift,
然而,这是非常,非常,非常容易迅速、
You literally just do this, And
你真的这样做,
when you get the value that comes back from that function,
当你回来从那个函数的值,
you just access the elements by name, Notice that when I
你只是访问元素的名字,注意到我
returned it in my code there in getSize, I didn't have to
在我的代码在getSize返回它,我不需要
give the names; I could if I wanted to,
给的名字,如果我想要,
I could have said return weight:150, height:, but
我可以返回重量说:150年,高度:,但是
I decided, eh, I'm just gonna return the values, Okay,
我决定,呃,我要返回的值,好,
another thing: range, range is an important little
另一件事:范围,范围是一个重要的小
struct in Swift: all that it represents is two end points,
在斯威夫特结构:它代表的是两个端点,
So a range is useful for, for example, a selection of text,
所以一个范围是有用的,例如,文本的选择,
where the selection starts and where the selection ends,
选择的选择开始和结束的地方,
It's also good for a sub-slice of an array, If you've got
也有利于sub-slice数组,如果你有
array of 100 elements, you might want the 15th to
100个元素的数组,您可能想要15
the 40th one, so you could specify that range, 15 to 40,
40人,所以您可以指定范围内,15 - 40岁
So range is this really simple little struct, which kind of
所以这真的是简单的结构,哪一种
looks like this, I say kind of, because it's a little more
是这样的,我说,因为这是一点
complicated than this, but it basically looks like this,
比这个复杂,但基本上是这样的,
It's a generic type like array because of course, you can
这是一个泛型类型数组因为当然,你可以
have a range of ints, You could have a range of floats,
有一个整数范围,你可以有一个范围的浮动,
You could have a range of strings even, Okay, so
你甚至可以有一个范围的字符串,所以
that T right there could be float, float, int,
这T可以浮动,浮动,int,
string, T is restricted a little bit, and I haven't
字符串,T是限制一点,我没有
really talked about how you restrict a generic type,
真正谈论你如何限制一个泛型类型,
But that T is restricted,
但这T是受限制的,
and it has to be what's called comparable, That's because
这是所谓的可比性,这是因为
range needs to make sure that the start index is less than
需要确保范围开始指数小于
the end index, That's part of what a range is defined to be,
的指数,定义范围的一部分,
So that T has to be something that can be compared
所以T是可以比较的东西
to see if the start index is less than the end index,
是否开始指数小于最后指数,
minor thing there, So, for example, a range of int
小的事情,所以,举个例子,int
would be great for specifying a range in an array,
将数组中指定一个范围大,
cuz an array is indexed by integers, right, starting at 0
因为数组是由整数索引,从0开始
and going up to the number of things in the array,
和数组中的许多事情,
Now there are other more powerful, more capable ranges,
现在还有其他的更强大,更有能力范围,
like CountableRange, A CountableRange is
像CountableRange CountableRange
just like a range, except for that you can count through
就像一个范围,除了可以通过计数
intermediate values between the start and the end,
开始和结束之间的中间值,
Okay, it's like a range of ints, A CountableRange means
好吧,这就像一系列整数,CountableRange的意思
the begin point and end point and one point each,
开始点和结束点,一个点,
Now as you stride through that range, it depends on what
你现在大步穿过范围,这取决于
the type is, Striding through a range of ints is different
通过一系列整数类型,大步是不同的
then striding through a range of floats, or striding through
然后大步通过一系列漂浮,或大步
a range of strings, There's a little difference there, and
一系列字符串,有一点点的差别,
we'll talk about that in a minute,
我们将讨论在一分钟,
There's a special syntax for
有一个特殊的语法
doing range, which is "dot dot less-than" or "dot dot dot",
做的范围,这是“点点小于号”或“点点点”,
Dot Dot Less-than means that you put the start index and
点点小于意味着你把指数和开始
the end index on either side of the dot dot less than,
最后指数点点不到的两侧,
And that means go from the start index to the end index,
这意味着从一开始指数指数,
but don't include the end index, not inclusive of it,
但不包括指数,而不是包容,
and the dot dot dot includes both ends, So for
和点点点包括两端,因此
example, in an array, let's have an array of four strings,
在一个数组,让我们有一个数组的四根弦,
a, b, c, d, and let's say that I want to get the c and
a,b,c,d,假设我想要得到c
the d out of there, I can say array sub, ( just
d,我可以说数组下标,(只是
like how I can say array sub 5 or array sub 3 is the fourth
喜欢我可以说数组下标5或数组下标3是第四
index of the array), I can also specify a range and
数组的索引),我还可以指定一个范围
get a sub array, a slice of the array, it's called, So
得到一个下标数组,数组的一片,这叫做
I can say 2,,,3, which means index 2 in the array,
我能说2、3,这意味着指数2数组中,
which is c because a is index 0, b is index 1, c is index 2,
c,因为索引0,b是指数1 c是指数2
dot dot dot index 3, which is the d inclusive, cuz it's dot
点点点指数3 d的包容,因为点
dot dot, And then the less than 1 would be exclusive,
点点,然后将独家小于1,
so that's why the d wouldn't be included in that one, So
这就是为什么d不会被包括在这个,
see how I'm using a range to get a sub slice of an array,
看看我用一系列子块数组,
that's kind of cool, By the way,
这是很酷的,顺便说一下,
if you say give me the array from 6,,,8,
如果你说给我一个数组从6日、8日
that's going to crash at run time with an array index out
的崩溃在运行时间和数组索引
of bounds because this array only has four elements, So
的界限,因为这个数组只有四个元素,所以
just because I'm accessing this subscripting with a range
只是因为我访问这个加下标范围
instead of with a number, it still has to be in bounds,
而不是一个数字,它仍有界限,
And then if I say array[4,,,1],
然后如果我说数组(4,1),
that also will crash at run time, because the range
在运行时也会崩溃,因为范围
is going to look at that and say I can't create a range
看那,说我不能创建一个范围
where the start value is greater than the end value,
开始值大于结束值,
can't be a backwards range, that's why that type like
不能向后范围,这就是为什么这样呢
int has to be comparable, of course you can compare ints,
int可比,当然你可以比较整数,
One thing very important to understand: a string,
理解一件事情非常重要:一个字符串,
a subrange of a string is not a range of ints,
子界的一个字符串不是一个整数范围,
You might think it is, right, I've got this string,
你可能认为这是对的,我有这个字符串,
100 characters, you might think strings sub 15 to 40
100个字符,你可能认为字符串子15 - 40
would be the 15th character to the 40th, And
将15字符40,
it's not: a string subrange is a range of string,index,
这不是:子范围是一系列字符串,字符串索引,
which is a different little data type, and
这是一个不同的数据类型,和
I'm going to talk all about that in a few slides,
我要谈的关于几张幻灯片,
But I just want to make it really clear,
但我只是想让它非常清楚,
that it is possible to say string subrange start,,<end,
可能就是说字符串子界开始,,<结束,
but start and end are not ints, they're string,indexes,
但是开始和结束不是整数,字符串索引,
and we'll see how that works, If the type
我们将会看到这是如何工作的,如果类型
of the range that you create with dot dot less than or
您创建的范围与点点小于
dot dot dot, if that type is an int, (actually,
点点点,如果这类型是int,(事实上,
if it's strideable by int, they can be strided by int so
如果是strideable int,int可以向他们
it's not gonna be float, but I'm not really prepared to
不会浮动,但我不准备
talk to you about strideable), but if the range has
和你谈谈strideable),但如果有范围
ints on either end, so it's a range from 2 to 7, for
整数在两端,所以这是一个范围从2到7日
example, then it automatically creates that countable range,
例子,那么它会自动创建可数范围,
that more capable range,
更有能力范围,
That range then becomes what's called a sequence, And
这个范围就变成了所谓的序列,和
sequences can be iterated through or enumerated, and
可以遍历序列或枚举
the way you do that is with "for in", so Swift's for
你这样做的方式是用“的”,如此迅速的
statement, this is the only one there is, It's called
声明中,这是唯一的一个,它叫
"for in" and all it ever means is, I want to go and enumerate
“在”,它的意思是,我想去和列举
all the values of a sequence, I'm going to talk about what
所有序列的值,我要讲什么
things that can be sequenced, Countable range is 1,
事情可以测序,可数范围是1,
because if an int goes from 0 to 7, and
因为如果int从0到7日
it's a countable range, then it can go 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
可数的范围,那么它可以0,1,2,3,4,5,6,
7, Arrays are sequences, sequences of their elements,
7、数组序列,序列的元素,
So you can "for in" through an array, Dictionaries are also,
所以你可以“在”,通过一个数组,字典也,
and we'll see that a little later, So here's how you do
稍后我们将会看到,这是你如何做
a normal C-like for loop, for (i = 0; i < 20; i++),
正常的c for循环,(我= 0;< 20;我+ +),
You cannot do that in Swift, that syntax simply doesn't
你不能在斯威夫特,语法并不简单
exist, Instead you would say for i in the range 0,,<20,
存在,相反你会说因为我在0,,< 20日
because notice I said it's less than 20, not less than or
因为注意我说的是小于20,不小于
equal to 20, so 0,,<20 means go through that, And so
0,等于20日,< 20意味着经历,所以
that little block of code is going to be executed once for
那个小的代码块将会执行一次
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, all the way up to number 19, so
0、1、2、3、4日一直到19日,数量
that's same thing as what you see there,
这是你所看到的一样,
Now what about floats? Floats are a little weird,
浮点数呢?
What if I wanted to do for,
如果我想做,
Whoa, how am I gonna do that? I can't, for
哇,我要怎么做呢?
example, say for i in 0,5,,,15,25,
例子,说因为我在0、5、15、25日,
How does it know to go by 0,3? And the answer is, it doesn't,
它怎么知道去到0,3 ?
In fact, a range like that, 0,5,,,15,25 is not a countable
事实上,这样一个范围,0、5、15、25不是可数
range, it's just range, It only knows the start and end,
范围,只是范围,它只知道开始和结束,
it knows nothing about what's in between, so
它是什么,一无所知
it cannot be a sequence, it can't be for in over, But
它不能一个序列,它不能在,但是
luckily, there's this great global function called stride,
幸运的是,有这个伟大的全局函数叫做步伐,
Stride takes a from and a to, or a through,
大步从和一个,或通过,
(depending whether you wanna go through to the end,
(这取决于你想要走到最后,
or just to to and not including it), and
或者,不包括),和
a by, which is, what it's going to step by,
由,,一步,
So here, I say stride from 0,5 through 15,25,
这里,我说大步从0,5 - 15日,25日
because I want less than or equal to, by 0,3, and
因为我想要小于或等于,0,3,
that's gonna create a new object, it's a CountableRange,
要创建一个新对象,这是一个CountableRange,
Now it's a special CountableRange, it knows
现在是一个特殊的CountableRange,它知道
how to count from 0,25 to 15,25 by that 0,3 step, You
如何计算从0、25 - 15 0,25的3步,你呢
don't need to worry about how it implements it, Stride just
不需要担心如何实现它,一步而已
creates you a CountableRange, Actually this will be called
创建CountableRange,实际上这将被调用
a ClosedCountableRange because it counts through to the end,
ClosedCountableRange因为它计数到最后,
so it's a dot dot dot kind of range of a dot dot
所以它是一种点点点的范围的点点
less than kind of range, So I have a CountableRange, and
不到的范围,所以我有一个CountableRange,
it's a sequence, so I can for in it, so I say for i in,
序列,这样我就可以了,所以我说我的,
Stride, I'd probably say for f in, or even better than f or
脚步,我可能说f,甚至比f或更好
i, A lot of times, by the way, on my slides, I'm gonna use
很多时候,我顺便说一下,在我的幻灯片,我要使用
variables like i or x or d because I want it to fit on my
变量如我或者x或d,因为我希望它适合我
slide, I don't want it to be wrapping, It's hard for you to
幻灯片,我不希望它是包装,对你来说是很困难的
read the slide if the code's always wrapping around, so
读幻灯片如果代码总是包装,
just because you see me using i and d and f doesn't mean
仅仅因为你看到我使用我和d和f并不意味着
that's license to have those kind of terrible names for
这是许可这些可怕的名称
your variables, You need to have meaningful names, So
你的变量,所以,你需要有意义的名称
that's how for in works here,
这就是因为在这里工作,
because stride is gonna return a CountableRange,
因为脚步会返回一个CountableRange,
ClosedCountableRange in this case, So
ClosedCountableRange在这种情况下,
that's how you do your standard for loops from C,
这就是你从C标准循环,
Alright, let's talk about the data structures in Swift,
好吧,让我们来谈谈迅速的数据结构,
You've already learned about three of the four of them,
你已经学习了三四个,
which are classes, structures, and enums, In our lecture,
类、结构、枚举,在我们的讲座,
we already did all three of those things,
我们已经做了所有这些东西,三个
We had a class, which is our view controller subclass,
我们有一个类,它是我们的视图控制器子类,
We had a struct, which is our calculator brain,
我们有一个结构体,这是我们的计算器的大脑,
And we had enum, which was our operation,
我们有枚举,这是我们的操作,
The fourth one is protocols, and
第四个是协议,
I'm not gonna talk about that until next week or
我不会谈论,直到下周或
even the week after, Protocols are super, duper important,
甚至一周后,协议非常重要的支持,
I don't want to make it sound like they're not important,
我不想让它听起来像他们不是重要的,
But they're new to a lot of you, and so I'm gonna try and
但是他们新给你很多,所以我要努力
ease you in with these ones that are more familiar,
缓解你的这些那些更熟悉,
although different in Swift probably than what you're used
虽然在斯威夫特不同可能比你使用
to, they're still more familiar to you,
他们更熟悉的你,
Let's just review quickly these three structs and what's
让我们快速回顾这三种结构是什么
the same and different about them, So what's the same?
相同的和不同的,相同的是什么?
They're declared very,
他们宣布,
very similar: they have different key word, but
非常相似:他们有不同的关键词,但是
they're almost exactly the same,
他们几乎完全一样,
The only difference really is a class can specify a super
唯一的区别是一个类可以指定一个超级
class, otherwise they're declared exactly the same,
类,否则他们宣布完全相同,
They can all have properties and functions, So,
他们都可以具有属性和功能,所以,
they're all very similar in that way, The only thing here
他们都非常相似,唯一
is that there cannot be any stored properties in an enum,
是不能有任何属性存储在一个枚举,
Enum keeps any data it has in associated values, so it can't
枚举使任何数据值有关,所以它不能
have any stored properties, but it can have computed
有任何存储属性,但它可以计算吗
properties and they certainly all can have functions,
属性和他们肯定都有功能,
Another thing that's very similar is they can all
另一件事是非常相似的,他们都可以
have initializers except enums, Enums don't need
初始化枚举除外,枚举不需要吗
an initializer cuz you just say the case you want, but
初始化器因为你只是说你想要的,但是
structs and classes have initializers, Okay, so
结构体和类初始化器,所以
that's the same, Now what are the differences?
这是一样的,现在的区别是什么?
Well of course, inheritance is a big difference for classes,
当然,类的继承是一个很大的区别,
Classes have inheritance, Structs and enums do not, But
类继承,结构和枚举,但是
the most important difference, which I mentioned last time,
最重要的区别,我上次提到的,
is that structs and enums are value types, and
结构体和枚举值类型,
classes are reference types, So let's go into that and talk
类是引用类型,所以让我们进入聊天
about it just a little more, It's so important, I'm gonna
关于这一点,很重要,我要
talk about it again, A value type, what does that mean?
讨论一遍,一个值类型,这意味着什么?
It means that it's copied when you pass it as an argument
这意味着它的复制,当你把它作为参数
It's copied, even if you just assign it to another variable,
这是复制的,即使你只是将其分配给另一个变量,
to a function,
一个函数,
it gets copied, If you assign it to a let, it's immutable,
它被复制,如果你把它赋值给一个让,它是不可变的,
that's very important to understand, If you assigned
理解是非常重要的,如果你分配
a value type to a let, using let x equal that thing,
让一个值类型,使用让x =,
you just made it immutable, No matter how complicated it is,
你做到了不变的,无论多么复杂,
If it's an array or dictionary,
如果它是一个数组或字典,
you can't add any elements, If it's a calculatorBrain,
你不能添加任何元素,如果它是一个计算器大脑
it means you can't call any of its mutable functions, So
这意味着你不能调用任何可变的函数,所以
you can't do perform operation on it, Now in assignment two,
你现在不能做执行运算,在分配两个,
I'm gonna have you add a method to the calculator brain
我要你添加一个方法计算器大脑
that is gonna let you use the calculator brain when it's
会让你使用计算器的大脑的时候
immutable, which is kinda cool, You still wouldn't be
不可变的,有点酷,你仍然不会
able to perform operation but you can be able to something
能够执行的操作但是你可以可以
very important, immutably, Now because of this, this kind of
非常重要,永恒地,现在由于这个原因,这种的
copyright-on-write behavior of value types, you must,
copyright-on-write值类型的行为,你必须,
of course, mark all the functions that are going to
当然,马克会的所有功能
modify it as mutating, And that's how the Swift knows,
修改它为变异,如何迅速的人都知道,
"Oops, I've gotta make a copy of this, an actual real copy,
“哎呀,我要复制,一个实际的真实的拷贝,
if someone writes to it", Now a reference class is pretty
如果有人写道,“,现在一个引用类很漂亮
different in that it gets stored in the heap somewhere
不同,因为它被存储在堆中
with a pointer to it, and when you pass it around to
用一个指针指向它,当你通过它周围
a function or to assign it to another variable or something
一个函数或者将它分配给另一个变量
like that, you're just passing a pointer around to it,
像这样,你只是传递一个指针,
Now, by the way, when you say, let x equal a reference type,
现在,顺便说一下,当你说,让x =一个引用类型,
you can still send it messages that will mutate it,
你仍然可以发送消息,变异,
All you're saying is the pointer can't change, but
所有你说的是指针不能改变,但是
what it points to can always be changed,
点什么总是可以改变,
Now reference types are what you're used to,
现在你使用引用类型,
Most languages that have object-oriented reference
大多数语言面向对象的引用
types, Reference types are a little bit Wild West- I
类型,引用类型是西部——我一点
don't have time to teach you this, I hope you'll get to see
没有时间教你这个,我希望你能看到
this sometime in your career at Stanford, but
这在你的职业生涯在斯坦福大学,但是
there is a different way of thinking about programming
有一种不同的思考方式编程
than you're used to: it's called functional programming,
你习惯:它被称为函数式编程,
How many people have heard the phrase,
有多少人听到这句话,
functional programming? So about half of you, The idea
函数式编程吗?
of functional programming is: you don't want this Wild West
函数式编程是:你不想要这蛮荒的美国西部
where you've got these objects with multiple people pointing
你有和多人指出这些对象吗
at them, any of whom could modify it at any time,
其中,任何可以随时修改它,
That leaves you open to a lot of difficulty in verifying
这让你打开很多难以验证
the correctness of your program,
你的程序的正确性,
Whereas if you have a lot of objects that are immutable,
而如果你有很多的对象是不可变的,
you know they can't change, and their APIs are basically
你知道他们不能改变,基本上都是和他们的api
like mathematical functions where data goes in and
像数学函数数据和
predictable data comes out, because there's
可预测的数据出来,因为有
not all this side-effecting, data-effecting other objects
并不是所有的副作用,data-effecting其他对象
that someone else is pointing to in all this,
别人是指向在这一切的事,
It's this really well-contained little thing,
这真的完全包含的小东西,
Now iOS was not developed with functional programming in mind
现在iOS不是发达与函数式编程
at all, But the people who invented Swift,
,而是发明了迅速的人,
they were thinking about functional programming, So
他们思考函数式编程,所以
you can kind of mix a lot of the elements of
你可以混合大量的元素
functional programming into your application,
函数式编程到您的应用程序,
if you're building an iOS application, Now that's a new
如果你构建一个iOS应用程序,这是一个新的
frontier in iOS, because for however long, 20 years,
在iOS前沿,因为不过久,20年,
really, or 30 years, really, if you consider all the way
真的,或30年,真的,如果你考虑
back to the invention of the technology that led to iOS,
回到技术的发明导致了iOS,
people have been programming with basically
人被编程
reference types only, for their object-orienting,
引用类型,对象,
But when you do this programming with structs and
但是当你这样做的编程结构和
enums, and especially when you throw in protocols, (which I
枚举,特别是当你把协议,(我
told you I was gonna tell you that are very important, but
告诉你我想告诉你,是非常重要的,但是
I cannot explain to you yet, and generics),
我无法向你解释,泛型),
when you start throwing those things all in there, you can
当你开始把这些东西都在那里,你可以
really do a good job of doing real functional programming,
真的很好做真正的函数式编程,
All of the Swift foundation is really designed with a lot
所有的斯威夫特基金会是真的有很多设计的
Swift 的基础框架中很多是基于
of functional programming in mind, If you ever really wanna
函数式编程的思想,如果你真的想要
函数式编程思想设计的。如果你想
kind of see a good example of how to apply this immutability
看到一个很好的例子,如何应用这种不变性
看更多关于如何实现这种不可变性
and generics, and protocols and all that stuff to build
和泛型,协议和所有这些东西
和在泛型、协议这些基础上搭建
an architecture, chase down all the things that
一个架构,找出所有的事情
的体系的例子，就去查看
are going on in the foundation library: string and range and
正在进行的基础库:字符串和范围
基础库中的实现方法，String、Range
all these things, Remember, that I said things like
所有这些事情,记住,我这样说
等所有内容。记住我说的类似于
the range is a sequence, or this thing is comparable,
范围是一个序列,或相当,
记得我说过（在 SE-0065 之前）Range 是 Sequence
remember how I said things like that? Okay, well,
还记得我说类似的东西?
或者这个是 Comparable 的之类的吗？好，接下来
how do you express that? You use protocols,
你怎么表达呢?
如何表达这些概念？你可以使用 Protocol（协议）
with these immutable types, that can be immutable and
与这些不可变类型,可以不变
和那些不可变的类型
use generics, So I can't explain all that,
使用泛型,所以我无法解释这一切,
以及 Generic（泛型）。我并不能在此一一解释
I've already spent too much time on it than I have to even
我已经花了太多的时间甚至比我
因为已经花了太多时间在这些概念上，超过我
talk about it in the lecture today, but just so
谈论今天的讲座,但仅仅如此
应该在今天的课程中讲解的内容，但是
you know, there is a huge advantage of programming in
你知道,有一个巨大的优势的编程
你们知道的，有时换一种编写代码的方式
a different way; it requires a real mindset change,
一种不同的方式,它需要一个真正的心态变化,
会带来巨大的好处。这需要观念上的改变。
So hopefully, you'll take a class where maybe the whole
希望,你会上课,也许整个
希望你们有机会写一个类，里面全部内容
class is functional programming,
类是函数式编程,
都基于函数式编程思想
and really you'll get a feel for it,
真的,你会得到一个感觉,
这样你们就会对这个概念有一定认识了。
Swift does a good job of supporting for
迅速做一份好工作的支持
Swift 在基础层面已经对函数式编程
the fundamentals you need to do that, That's kind
基础你需要这样做,这是
提供了你需要的支持。对于应该怎么选择编程思想
of the long-winded answer to which do you choose, If you're
你选择的冗长的回答,如果你
我已经给出了长篇大论式的解答。如果你
doing more of a functional approach, even if you're doing
做更多的功能的方法,即使你做的事情
正在学习更多关于函数式编程的知识，或者只是
a reference-based approach like what you're used to, try
reference-based方法像你,试一试
了解传统的基于引用的思想，都可以尝试
to lean towards immutability, try to ask yourself,
倾向于不变性,试着问自己,
向这种不可变的方式上转变。试着问自己
can this thing work and be immutable? Is there some
这个东西能和不变的工作吗?
这些内容不可变后还能正常运作吗？是否有
functionality in my program that I could share by creating
功能在我的项目,我可以通过创建分享
一些功能可以通过泛型来共享其实现部分
a generic, for example, At least those leanings
一个通用的,例如,至少那些倾向
这种思想上的转变至少
might help you build the apps that are more testable,
可能会帮助您构建应用程序更可测试的,
会帮助你构建更具有可测试性的应用
because it's a lot easier to write a test for
因为它是更容易编写一个测试
这会让测试变得更容易
something that's like a mathematical function where
就像一个数学函数的东西
例如一个数学相关的函数
you know the data out is supposed to be the same for
你知道的数据应该是相同的
如果可以确认数据在经过处理后
the data in, than it is for something where there's
的数据,比那里的
和传入时保持相同，会比那些
a lot of data that you have to set everything up, Set this,
大量的数据,你必须设置一切,设置这个,
需要设置很多输入数据的要容易的多。预先设置这个
set this and this and this, and now call the method,
设置这个,这个和这个,现在调用该方法,
这个以及这个，然后调用方法
that's a lot more difficult to write test cases for, etc,
这是一个更难以编写测试用例,等等,
为这样的方法编写测试用例会非常困难
So that's value and reference, Let's talk a little bit about
这就是价值和参考,让我们谈谈
以上说的是值和引用。接下来讲一些
the syntax of methods, I'm gonna go fast on this,
语法的方法,我要快,
方法的语法。我会加快一些速度
Hopefully, you all understand this,
希望大家理解这一点,
希望你们可以理解这些内容
All parameter names have external names and internal
所有的参数名称和内部外部的名字
所有的参数包含外部参数名和内部参数名
names, The internal name is used inside the definition, or
名字,内部使用的内部名称定义,或
内部参数名用于函数的声明
the inside the implementation of the function,
函数的内部实现,
或函数内容的实现部分
So here I have these two functions, foo and bar, Bar
这里我有这两个函数,foo和bar,酒吧
有两个函数，foo 和 bar。bar 调用了 foo
calls foo, So you can see that inside foo's implementation,
调用foo,所以你可以看到,在foo的实现,
所以在 foo 的内部
it is using the first and the second, whereas bar,
它是使用第一个和第二个,而酒吧,
它用了 first 和 second 作为参数名，但是
when bar calls foo, it uses external first and
当酒吧调用foo,它使用外部首先
bar 调用 foo 时， 使用了 externalFirst 和
external second, as the names of the items, And you know
外部第二,物品的名字,你知道的
externalSecond 作为参数名
that you can put an under bar to make it so there's no
你可以把一个在酒吧所以没有
你可以在没有外部参数名时
external name, We only do that 99,99% of the time with
外部的名字,我们只做99,99%的时间
用下划线来代替。这种下划线的方式我们99.99%的时候只对
the first item, Why do we do it? Because sometimes the name
第一项,我们为什么这样做?
第一个参数使用。为什么要这样做？因为有时通过函数名
of the method, and/or the type of that first argument, is
的方法,和/或第一个参数的类型的
或者第一个参数的类型
enough to make it clear what that thing is supposed to be,
足以让它清楚的事情应该是,
已经可以明确的推断出第一个参数应该是什么
so we don't need to put an external name,
所以我们不需要把外部的名字,
这时我们就没必要写外部参数名了
It's kinda clear, All the other parameters,
它有点清晰,所有其他参数,
这样显得更清晰。对于其它参数
we don't have the advantage of having the name of the method
我们没有优势的方法的名称
把参数名省略只留函数名没什么好处
there, So that's why we almost never put underbar for
在那里,这就是为什么我们几乎从不把下划线
所以几乎不会在除第一个参数名之外的地方
the later ones, By the way, if you only put one
后来的,顺便说一下,如果你只放一个
使用下划线。顺带，如果只写了一个
parameter name, then that's both the external name and
参数名称,那么外部的名字和
参数名，那么这个名称既是外部参数名
the internal name, and that's not that uncommon,
内部名称,并不少见,
也是内部参数名，这种情况并不罕见
you'll do that occasionally, All right, so you know all
偶尔你会这样做,好吧,你知道
可以偶尔使用。好了，这些就是全部
that, When it comes to doing overriding, subclassing, in
做覆盖时,子类化,
接下来是重写和子类
reference types and classes, when you override, you have to
引用类型和类,覆盖时,你必须
对于引用类型和对象，可以重写
explicitly let Swift know that you know you're doing that,
明确让迅速知道你知道你这样做,
你必须明确地让 Swift 知道你要重写
And you do that by putting the override keyword,
你这样做将覆盖关键字,
要用 override 关键字
So if you override a method from your superclass you have
如果你从超类覆盖一个方法
所以，如果你要重写一个父类的方法
to say override func whatever, You can mark a method or
说覆盖函数,您可以标记方法或
必须使用 override func。可以将一个方法或
even a whole class final, and that means that it cannot be
即使是全班最后,意味着它不能
整个类标记为 final，这意味着它无法
overridden, subclasses will not be allowed to override it,
覆盖,不允许子类覆盖它,
被重写，子类不允许重写它
Most languages have that, Now on the topic of methods,
大多数语言都有,现在主题的方法,
大部分语言拥有这类语法。继续方法这个主题
You've seen, actually you've seen both, but mostly seen and
您所看到的,实际上你已经看过,但大多见过和
可以看到，实际上两个都在这里，但是通常你们更熟悉
understood instance methods, These are methods,
理解实例方法,这些方法,
实例方法。实例方法
or vars, that are being sent to an instance of the class
或var,正在送往类的一个实例
或实例变量，可以通过给一个类
struct or enum, In other words, one of them,
结构体或枚举,换句话说,其中一个,
结构体或枚举的实例发送消息来访问。也就是给某一个具体对象
Like I create one of them: I create a double of 15,5,
就像我创建其中之一:我创建一个15双,5,
比如我可以创建它们的一个实例：我创建一个值为 15.5 的 Double
I have one, and I can send it messages,
我有一个,我可以发送消息,
我有了一个实例，就可以给它发送消息
But types, like the type double, the type string,
但类型,比如双类型,类型字符串,
但是类型，例如 Double，String
the type calculator brain, they can also have methods and
计算器大脑类型,他们也可以有方法和
CalculatorBrain，它们也可以拥有方法和
vars, Computed vars, no storage, but computed vars,
var计算var,没有存储,但计算var,
变量。计算变量，没有存储空间，是计算得出的变量
All you do to add a method or a var to a type is
你添加一个方法或一个var类型
要给类型添加方法或变量，只要
you put static in front of the declaration,
你把静态的声明,
将 static 关键字放在声明语句前面即可
So "static func whatever" means this is a function on
所以“静态函数无论”意味着这是一个函数
static func 意思是这个方法
the type, not on instances of the type, on the type itself,
的类型,而不是实例类型,类型本身,
属于类型。不属于实例，是类型本身的方法
For example, let's think about double here,
例如,让我们考虑双,
还是以 Double 举例
Double actually has quite a few static or type methods and
双有不少方法和静态或类型
Double 拥有不少类型方法和
vars, You access them by sending the message to
var,通过将消息发送到您访问它们
变量。可以通过发送消息给
Double to the actual word, capital D-O-U-B-L-E, You
双实际的话,资本D-O-U-B-L-E,你
Double 来访问。一字不差，D-O-U-B-L-E
don't send it to an instance, you send it to that word, And
不要寄给一个实例,你寄给这个词,
不要发送给一个实例，而是发送给那个类型的名称
you've already seen at least one of these, which was pi,
你已经看到至少其中之一,这是π,
你已经看到过至少一个例子了，比如 π
Remember we said Double,pi and we got the value of pi?
记得我们说双,π,π的值?
还记得我们通过 Double.pi 取得到了 π 的值吗？
Pi is a var, a computed var, on the class or
π是一个var计算var,类或
π 是一个变量，一个计算变量
struct actually, double, but it also has other methods,
结构实际上,双,但它也有其他方法,
属于 Double 这个结构体。Double 也有一些其它方法
like abs, Abs takes a double value and
如abs,abs双重价值
例如 abs。abs 接收一个 Double 的值
returns the absolute value of it, That is on the type,
返回它的绝对值,类型,
返回这个值的绝对值。这是类型的方法
You say Double,abs, Double,pi, As opposed to, for example,
你说双、abs、翻倍,π,而不是,例如,
可以用 Double.abs，Double.pi。但是
if I have a double like x is equal 23,85,
如果我有双像x = 23日,85年,
如果我有一个 Double 类型的实例 x，它等于 23.85
So x is now a double, I can't say x Double,pi cause
所以x现在是双,我不能说x双,π的原因
x 是一个 Double 实例。这时不能通过 x 调用 Double.pi
x is an instance of a double, You see the difference?
x是一个双重的实例,你可以看到区别了吗?
因为 x 是 Double 的一个实例。你们是否明白了其中的区别？
We see saying x,pi, trying to send pi
我们看到说x,π,试图把π
如果我们说 x.pi，尝试把 pi 发送给
to an instance versus sending pi to a type double,
一个实例与发送π型双,
实例，对比发送 pi 给类型 Double 的区别
So what do we use these type methods for?
我们使用这些类型的方法?
为什么要用类型方法？
Well, we can't access any instance variables because
好吧,我们不能访问任何实例变量,因为
我们没法访问任何一个实例变量
we're not sending them to an instance,
我们不发送一个实例,
因为我们没有给实例发送消息
We mostly use them for utility methods, things like that,
我们主要使用的实用方法,类似这样的事情,
类型方法通常是类中的辅助方法，比如
Constants like pi is a good example, Things that
常数π是一个很好的例子,事情
常量，π 就是一个很好的例子。还有那些
kind of are functions that are associated with this type but
这种类型的函数
和这个类型本身关联
don't belong to a particular instance or
不属于一个特定的实例或
但不属于任何一个特定的实例
wouldn't really operate on an instance, Now for example,
现在真的不会操作实例,比如,
或者不会真的对一个实例进行操作的方法。例如
you might have an instance method or
你可能有一个方法或实例
可以有一个实例方法
even an instance var called abs, A-B-S, with no arguments,
甚至一个实例变量称为abs,A-B-S,不带参数,
或一个实例变量叫做 abs，A-B-S，没有参数
That you would send to an instance, and it would take
你会发送到一个实例,它将采取
当你调用它时，它会
the absolute value of the thing you sent it to, But
你寄给的绝对值,但是
取这个实例的绝对值
of course the type one has to have an argument because
当然有一个论点,因为类型
但是类型方法需要接受一个参数
you're sending it to the type double,
你发送给双类型,
因为你发送消息给 Double 类型
so there's no double involved,
所以不涉及双,
所以并没有 Double
There's no instance of a double involved, Everybody got
没有涉及的两个实例,每个人都有
没有 Double 实例参与计算
that? Alright: properties, You know all about properties,
了吗?
所有人都明白了吗？属性，你们都知道什么是属性
We saw computed properties like display value in
我们看到像显示值在计算属性
我们已经看过了计算属性，比如之前计算器中
our calculator, There's actually some really cool
我们的计算器,有一些很酷的
用来显示的数值。属性有一些非常棒的特性
features on properties, One of the most interesting ones is
功能属性,其中最有趣的是
其中最有趣的一个是
property observers, What is a property observer?
财产观察员,观察者属性是什么?
属性观察器。什么是属性观察器？
A property observer is a little piece of code that
一个属性观察者是一小段代码
属性观察器是一些代码
will get executed when your property changes,
时将会执行你的财产变化,
可以在属性改变的时候自动执行
Anytime your property changes just a little piece of code
任何时候你的财产变化只是一小段代码
任何时候属性改变了，这段代码
can get executed, Now you can actually find out
可以执行,现在你可以找到吗
就会被执行。你能准确地捕捉到
just before your property changes, Or
之前你的财产变化,或
属性将要改变之前，或者
you can find out just after your property changes,
你可以找到你的财产变化后,
属性刚刚改变之后
Or both, And the way you do this, and this works for
或者两者都是,你这样做,这工作
或者上述两种。这只能应用于
your stored properties, like userIs InTheMiddleOfTyping:
你的存储属性,像userIs InTheMiddleOfTyping:
存储属性，比如 userIsInTheMiddleOfTyping
we could put a property observer on there, and
我们可以把属性观察者在那里,
我们可以加一个属性观察器
execute some code every time we change that, It also works
执行一些代码每次我们改变,它也有效
每次它被改变都会执行一段代码。这个功能
for inherited properties, so if you inherit something
为继承的属性,所以如果你继承的东西
也对继承的属性有效，比如继承了某些
from your superclass, you can put these properties in and
从你的超类,您可以把这些属性
父类的属性，可以通过属性观察器
notice that it changed, By the way, if you have a property
注意,它改变了,顺便说一下,如果你有一个属性
观察它们的改变。顺便，如果属性
which is a value type, (a struct or
这是一个值类型(结构或
是值类型，如结构体
something, like an array or an dictionary), this property
的东西,就像一个数组或一个字典),这个性质
数组、字典等，这些属性观察器
observer stuff will happen if that thing gets changed,
观察者的东西如果那件事会发生改变,
会在它们指向的值被改变时
if it gets mutated, So if you add something to the array,
如果它发生突变,所以如果你的东西添加到数组,
或是包含的内容被改变时触发。比如向数组中添加元素
boom, the Property Observer will kick in and say,
繁荣,房地产将启动观察者说,
那就炸了，属性观察器会触发并告诉你
"that changed", How do these Property Observers
“改变”,这些财产如何观察员
“有东西改变了”。属性观察器是
work? They look a lot like a computed property, Remember
工作吗?
基于什么原理工作的呢？它们很像计算属性那样。还记得
that the computed property displayValue had get and
计算属性displayValue获取和
displayValue 的 get 方法执行时
then we had some code, And then we had set and
我们有一些代码,然后我们有集和
我们在 get 中加入了一些别的代码，set 的时候
we had some code? This is similar except for
我们有一些代码?
也是一样。这基本上是类似的，除了
get and set it's will set, or did set,
获取和设置将,还是集,
这个是 willSet 和 didSet
By the way, you probably would never (I don't even know if
顺便说一下,你可能永远不会(我甚至不知道
顺便，你可能永远不会（我也不知道
you can) use this in a computed property because
你可以),因为在计算中使用这个属性
是不是能这么做）将属性观察器用于计算属性，因为
you've got the set clause there so
所以你有一组条款
既然已经有了 set 语句
you can just put it right in set,
你可以把它设置,
完全可以将代码放在 set 里
You don't need to find out when it's set because you set
你不需要找出当它因为你集合
根本不需要去监视何时它被改变，因为只有你的 set 方法在改变它
it, But for stored properties and inherited properties,
但对于存储属性和继承的属性,
但是存储属性和继承来的属性不一样
that make sense, so you have willSet,
有意义的,所以你将确定,
这时属性观察器有存在价值，所以有了 willSet
Now, willSet, first of all, you put it all in a curly
现在,将确定,首先,你把它所有的花
现在，willSet，首先你要把大括号
brace after the property just like if you were doing
撑属性后就像如果你在干什么
放在属性的后面，像计算属性一样
a computed property but, this is not a computed property,
一个计算的属性,但这不是一个计算的属性,
但是这不是计算属性
just adding a curly brace doesn't make it a computed
只是添加一个花括号不计算
加上大括号不会让它变成计算属性
property, you have to put get or set in there, but,
财产,你必须把获取或设置,但是,
你要里面加上 get 或 set，但是
if I put willSet, then, inside that code,
那么,如果我把将确定在代码中,
如果在里面加上了 willSet
there's a special variable just like there in the set
有一个特殊的变量,就像在一组
会出现一个特殊的变量，和 set 计算属性时
case of computer property, called newValue, and
计算机属性,称为newValue,
的情况类似，叫做 newValue
that is the value that that thing is going to be set to,
这是那件事的价值将被设置为,
这个值将会被赋予给这个属性
It's not set yet, Some property,
未设置一些属性,
但是还没赋予给它。一些属性
see some stored property up there? It has not yet
看到一些存储属性?
看到上面那些存储属性了吗？它还没
been set to newValue but it's going to be, And then didSet,
被设置为newValue但这将是,然后didSet,
被设置成 newValue，但马上就要设置了
that code occurs after some property has been set and
这段代码后发生一些属性被设置
didSet 中的那些代码在属性被设置之后执行
the special variable in there is oldValue,
有oldValue特殊变量,
在那里特殊变量叫做 oldValue
That's the value it used to have before it got set, So
的价值之前有过去,
这个值是它被改变前的值
you can compare if they've changed, for
你可以比较他们是否已经改变,
你可以对比是否发生了变化
example, So where do we use these things?
的例子,所以我们用这些东西在哪里?
这些特性要用在哪里呢？
Probably the number one place that we use them is in our
可能一个地方,我们是我们的使用它们
可能最重要的一个用途是在
Controller in view, Let's say I'm a button and
控制器的视图,假设我是一个按钮,
控制视图中。比如，我是个按钮
my background color changes, I inherit my background color
我的背景颜色变化,我继承我的背景颜色
我的背景色改变了，我的背景色是继承自
from my super class, UI view, Up the chain of super classes,
从我的超类,用户界面视图,父类的链,
继承树最上层的父类 UIView 的
Every time the background color changes,
每次背景颜色的变化,
每次背景色改变时
the button wants to redraw itself so
按钮要重新绘制
这个按钮都想重绘自己
it will have var background color is a UI color,
它将var背景颜色是UI的颜色,
所以它有一个背景色属性，类型是 UIColor
open curly brace, didSet open curly brace
花括号,didSet花括号
添加一个大括号，didSet 再跟一个大括号
draw myself closed curly brace, Question? Okay,
画自己封闭的花括号,问题吗?
在这里重绘自身。有什么问题？
so the question is, if someone changes some stored property
问题是,如果有人改变一些存储属性
问题是，如果某人改变了存储属性
there, am I responsible for doing something about that
在那里,我负责做某事
我是否要负责在
in willSet or didSet? Do I have to actually set it? And
在将确定还是didSet ?
willSet 或 didSet 中做些什么？我是否真的要去设置它？
the answer is no, Okay, that's being set somewhere else,
答案是否定的,好吧,这是在别的地方,
答案是否。如果被别的什么地方改变了
You're just getting a chance to run some other code that
你只是得到一个机会来运行一些代码
你只是获得了一个机会去执行其它代码
you wanna run just before and just after it happens,
你想要它发生,只是之前和之后运行
你希望执行的是 set 前后的事情
But you're not responsible for setting the actual value,
但是你不是负责设置实际的值,
你无需负责 set 这件事本身
That's done for you, That's why you get to
这是为你做的,这就是你的原因
系统已经为你做好了，所以你得到是
see the old value and the new value in the two of them,
看到旧值和新值在他们两个,
oldValue 和 newValue
So we'll see this next week when we start drawing on
我们将会看到这个在下周当我们开始画
我们下周讲屏幕绘图之后会涉及这些
screen, where we're gonna be watching properties change so
屏幕,在那里我们将会看属性变化
那时我们会去观察属性改变
we can cause ourselves to redraw, Next, lazy properties,
我们可以使自己重新画,接下来,懒惰的属性,
来决定什么时候去调用自身的重绘。接下来，lazy（延时）属性
Lazy initialization is a really powerful tool,
延迟初始化是一个非常强大的工具,
延时初始化是一个强大的工具
It's gonna get you out of a lot of binds in this class,
它会给你很多的结合在这个类中,
这可以帮你减少很多的麻烦
What does it mean? A lazy var, a var
这是什么意思?
具体是什么意思？一个延时变量，是一个变量
that you say lazy in front of, whatever it's set equal to,
你说懒的,无论它集等于,
在前面加上 lazy 关键字，不管它被赋什么值
that equals doesn't actually happen until someone accesses
实际上等于没有发生直到有人访问
都不会真的立刻执行，直到某处访问了这个值
that var, Until someone asks for the value of that var,
var,直到有人问对于var的价值,
直到某处需要这个变量的值之前
it doesn't actually do the initialization there,
它实际上并不做初始化,
它都不会真的初始化
It doesn't do that equal something,
它没有这样做等于什么,
这和常规的赋值不一样
So it's lazy, It's waiting,
这是懒惰的,等待,
所以它是延时的。它会等待
Now why do you wanna be lazy? Well, one obvious reason
为什么你想偷懒吗?
为什么需要 lazy 呢？一个明显的原因
is like here, lazy var brain equals calculator
就像在这里,大脑懒惰var =计算器
像这样，lazy var brain = CalculatorBrain()
brain, what if calculator brain was really expensive to
大脑,如果计算器大脑非常昂贵
如果 CalculatorBrain 的创建非常耗资源
create, What if it opened a network connection because
创建,如果因为它开了一个网络连接
或者它会打开一个网络连接
we're going to share the calculation with the internet
我们要与互联网分享计算
我们会把计算结果共享至互联网
or something, you know what I mean,
之类的,你知道我的意思,
或者一些其它情况，你应该知道我的意思了
do something that is expensive,
做的东西是昂贵的,
总之就是做一些耗资源的操作
Well, you wouldn't want to do it,
好吧,你不想这样做,
好吧，你肯定不想这样做
unless someone actually tried to access the brain,
除非有人试图访问的大脑,
除非某处真的需要访问这个 brain
called set up operand on it or something, Then you would
叫设置操作数之类的,然后你会
调用设置操作数或者其它什么。这时你才
want to actually do the work to create it,
想做的工作来创建它,
想要真的创建它
Okay so one reason to be lazy,
好的,一个原因是懒惰,
这是一个需要 lazy 的理由
it's not that important of a reason it turns out, but
这不是原来的重要原因,但是
延后高消耗的操作这点
one is to delay expensive operations, But
一个是延迟昂贵的操作,但是
似乎并没有那么重要
what's another reason to do it? Well, in Swift,
这样做的另一个原因是什么?
但是另一个原因是，在 Swift 中
all vars have to be initialized, Remember that?
所有增值必须初始化,还记得吗?
所有的变量都要被初始化，还记得吗？
Remember we added userIsInTheMiddleOfTyping,
记得我们userIsInTheMiddleOfTyping补充说,
我们曾添加了 userIsInTheMiddleOfTyping
And we didn't say, equals false, And we got an error,
我们没有说,等于虚假,我们得到了一个错误,
我们没有让它等于 false，这时产生了一个错误
It said we had no init, because we hadn't initialized
它说我们没有初始化,因为我们没有初始化
说缺少构造器，因为我们没有初始化它
that, Not only did they all have to be initialized, but
,他们不仅必须被初始化,但是
不仅所有变量都要初始化，而且
they all had to be initialized before you could even send
他们都必须初始化之前,你甚至可以发送
属性要在可以被发送消息前初始化
a message to that class, even internally, So
类的消息,即使在内部,所以
即使在类内部也是如此
you can't invoke any of your own methods until you fully
你不能调用任何自己的方法,直到你完全
也就是你无法调用任何一个实例方法，直到
initialize yourself, What if one of the things you want to
初始化你自己,如果你想要的一件事
实例完全初始化了。如果你希望某个属性
initialize needs to call a method on yourself? It's
初始化需要调用一个方法吗?
的初始化过程调用另一个实例方法怎么办？
impossible, Because if you need to initialize something
不可能的,因为如果你需要初始化一些
这是不可能的。比如你需要初始化某个属性
to be allowed to send messages to yourself and you need
可以发送消息给你自己和你所需要的
才能来给实例发消息
to send a message to yourself to initialize something,
将消息发送给自己来初始化,
但这个属性的初始化，又要求实例已经完成了构造
it's a deadlock, You can't do it, Okay, well lazy let's you
这是一个僵局,你不能这样做,好吧,好懒的你
这就陷入了僵局。原本没法这么做，但是可以通过 lazy 实现
do it, Because you can say for example, the last one there;
这样做,因为你能说例如,最后一个;
比如用这里最后的 myProperty 举例
lazy my property equals some method on myself, This is not
懒惰的我的财产=一些方法我自己,这不是
将这个延时属性设置为实例的某个方法的值
going to be executed until someone says my property and
要直到有人说我的财产和执行
直到某人访问它之前，这段代码都不会运行
no one's allowed to access my property until I'm fully
没有人允许访问我的财产,直到我完全
记住，直到实例初始化完成之前，谁也不能访问这个属性
initialized, So by definition there's no way
初始化,所以没有办法定义
所以很明确
that that is gonna try to get initialized until I'm already
这是要把之前我已经初始化
在实例完全初始化之前，延迟属性一定没有初始化
fully initialized, And yet this lazy thing counts as this
完全初始化,但这懒惰的计数
但这时延时属性会被视作
thing having been initialized, So this is the big loophole,
已经初始化,这是一个巨大的漏洞,
已经初始化了。这是一个很大的“漏洞”
Lazy var myProperty counts as having been initialized
懒惰的var myProperty计数是初始化
延时属性被视为已初始化
even though it really hasn't yet, Because it's waiting for
即使它真的还没有,因为它是等待
但实际上它没被初始化，因为 myProperty 在等待
something to actually access myProperty, But it counts for
实际上访问myProperty,但计数
某处实际访问它。所以这个漏洞的存在
the purposes of that rule, so now someone comes along later
该规则的目的,现在再来一个人
是为了遵守那条规则。现在某处实际访问了它
and accesses it, now we can call this method, So
并访问它,现在我们可以调用这个方法
我们再调用这个方法
do you see how deferring the calling of this method in
你看看延迟调用该方法的在吗
你们理解了吗？推迟调用这个方法
order to initialize this gets us around that requirement
为了初始化这个让我们周围的要求
使得我们可以摆脱
that everything be initialized?
这一切都被初始化吗?
所有内容都要被初始化的限制
It's really tricky, And then the middle one there,
真的很棘手,然后中间的一个,
这真的有点复杂。中间这个
someProperty, that's super tricky, Because you can
someProperty,超级棘手,因为你可以
someProperty，它更复杂。你可以
actually have a closure, (remember what a closure is,
实际上有一个闭包,(记住什么是一个闭包,
用一个 closure（闭包），（回忆下什么是闭包
right from calculator brain, it's just a function,
从计算器大脑,它只是一个函数,
在 CalculatorBrain 中用到过，其实闭包就是函数
in line function), you can actually have a closure
功能),你可以关闭
一个内联函数），你可以用一个闭包
to initialize your thing lazily, All you do is you
延迟初始化您的事,所有你做的是你
来延时初始化一个变量。你要做的仅仅是
put the closure, open curly brace, close curly brace,
花括号将关闭,关闭花括号,
把闭包写在这里，开始大括号，结束大括号
It obviously has to return something of the type
它显然已经返回的类型
显然，还要返回符合这个变量类型的结果
of that var, And then just put the little open parenthesis,
var,然后把小左括号,
然后还要加上一对小括号
close parenthesis at the end, When we open parenthesis and
关闭括号结束时,当我们打开括号
在闭包的结尾
close parenthesis at the end of the closure,
关闭括号结束时关闭,
在闭包的结尾加上小括号
that means execute this closure right now, But
这意味着现在执行这个闭包,但是
意味着立刻执行这个闭包
it's not gonna execute right now, it's gonna act lazy so
现在它不会执行,它会懒惰所以行动
但是实际上它并不会立刻执行，因为它是延时执行的
it's gonna happen later, And that means that that closure
它会发生之后,这意味着关闭
它会稍后才被执行。这意味着
inside could reference self, Because self will be fully
里面可以参考自我,因为自我将完全
闭包内部可以引用 self。因为当这个闭包执行的时候
initialized by the time this closure gets executed,
初始化的时候这个闭包被执行,
self 肯定已经被完全初始化了
since it's lazily executed, So
因为它是延迟执行
前提是确保它是延时执行的
lazy will get you out of some of these tricky wickets,
懒惰会让你有些棘手的wicket,
lazy 可以使你摆脱这类棘手的处境
because when you see me talk about initialization,
因为当你看到我谈论初始化,
当你们听我讲到初始化时
you're gonna be like, "I don't want to do that, ever",
你要这样说,“我不想这么做,”,
你们可能会说“我永远不想那样做”
You're going to try and avoid it, and
你要试着避免它,
你们会尝试避免它
this is a good way to avoid it, So yeah,
这是一个好办法避免它,所以是的,
这就是一种很好的避免的方式
it still satisfies all those things, Alright, on to Array,
它仍然满足所有这些东西,好吧,数组,
它仍然满足所有规则。好了，下面讲 Array（数组）
Everybody knows what an array is, Everyone knows what
每个人都知道什么是数组,每个人都知道
所有人都知道数组是什么，所有人都知道泛型数组是什么
a generic array is, You just, when you declare the array,
一般的数组,你,当你声明数组,
你肯定知道，因为当你声明一个数组时
you have to say what type of things are gonna
你说要什么类型的东西
必须指明它的内容的类型是什么
be in the array, There's a different syntax though,
数组中,有不同的语法,
也有另一种语法
which I didn't introduce when I did dictionary in the demo,
我没有介绍当我做字典的演示,
之前的 demo 中，我用了字典，但是没有提到过这个语法
But you can declare an array, those two yellow things
但是你可以声明一个数组,这两个黄色的东西
你可以声明一个数组，上面黄色标注的两个声明方法
up there are exactly the same thing, So,
有完全相同的事情,所以,
是一样的
open square bracket,
开放的方括号,
左半方括号
string close square bracket is exactly the same as saying
字符串结束方括号是完全一样的
String，右半方括号
array angle bracket string, It's just kind of a special
尖括号的字符串数组,它只是一种特殊
这与 Array 加上一对尖括号，括起来 String，是等价的
way to declare an array and it actually seems to be
声明一个数组,它实际上似乎
[String] 这种声明数组的特殊方式更被大众接受
the preferred way, I actually prefer the other way because
的首选方法,实际上我更喜欢另一种方式,因为
但是我比较喜欢用 Array
it's a little clearer to you that are learning that this is
有点清晰的学习,这是你
更明确地告诉你们这些学生，这是个数组
an array, because it says the word array and string,
一个数组,因为它表示数组和字符串,这个词
毕竟包含了 Array 和 String 两个单词
But open square bracket, close square bracket,
但是开方括号,方括号,
不过中括号的方式
we know that's going to be index into an array so
我们知道的索引数组
我们知道这是通过索引访问数组元素的方式
it looks kind of array-ish but
它看起来有点array-ish但
它也看起来更有数组的风格
just get used to it, [String] means an array of string,
只是习惯,[String]意味着一个字符串数组,
习惯了就好了。[String] 代表一个包含字符串的数组
That's the name of that type
这是该类型的名称
这是字符串数组这个类型的名称
array of string, So if I had a string right here like
一系列字符串,所以如果我有一个字符串
如果我有一些字符串
this giraffe, cow, doggie, and bird, Four animals in here,
这只长颈鹿,牛,狗,鸟,四只动物在这里,
比如 Giraffe，Cow，Doggie，Bird 这四种动物
four strings and I said animals dot append ostrich,
四根弦,我说动物点附加鸵鸟,
四个字符串，然后我调用 animals.append("Ostrich")
well append appends something onto the array, now the thing
现在添加附加到数组的东西,
append 这个方法会将一些东西加入到数组中，
you are appending has to be the same type obviously
你是附加显然必须是相同的类型
你加入的新东西显然也必须
as the type of everything in the array, however the type
所有的类型的数组,但是类型
和数组中其它元素是同一个类型
was declared, Notice that animals is in inferred,
宣布,注意动物推断,
因为类型已经被声明了。注意这里 animals 的类型已经
By Swift, to be an array of string, Because Swift sees
迅速,是一个字符串数组,因为迅速看到
被 Swift 推断为 Array，因为 Swift
that you sent it to an array of things and
你寄给一个东西和数组
通过检查你在数组中包含的每一个元素
it looked at all the things and they were all strings,
它看着所有的东西,他们都是字符串,
判断出它们全都是字符串
So it said, the animals must be an array of string, Now,
所以说,动物必须是一个字符串数组,现在,
所以它断定，animals 必然是一个 Array
this line of code animals,append("Ostrich"),
这行代码的动物,附加(“鸵鸟”),
这行代码 animals.append("Ostrich")
That's very bad,
这是非常糟糕的,
存在问题
Can anyone tell me why that's not gonna work?
谁能告诉我为什么这不是要工作吗?
谁能告诉我它为什么有问题？
Yeah? >> That's exactly right,
是吗?
>> 答得好，给你颗糖吃
We define this animal's variable with let, so
让我们定义这个动物的变量,所以
我们声明 animals 时用的是 let
it's immutable, So when we say append an ostrich onto
它是不可变的,所以当我们说附加上鸵鸟
它是不可变的，所以我们 append("Ostrich")
an immutable thing, it's going to crash my program,
一个不变的东西,它会崩溃我的程序,
添加进这个不可变的数组，就会导致程序崩溃
But actually, it won't even crash my program,
但实际上,它甚至不会崩溃我的程序,
其实不会真的导致程序崩溃
It won't even compile,
它甚至不进行编译,
而是连编译都无法通过
Like, Swift compiler's just gonna say, no way,
快速编译器就会说,没办法,
Swift 编译器会告诉你，这样做不行
you can't do append of something or other,
你不能添加或其他的东西,
你没法 append 或者做其他操作
So that's a good one over there, you got that,
这是一个很好的一个,你明白我的意思,
这就是个很好的例子，你们已经掌握了
How about this one? I'll give you a second chance for
这一个怎么样?
那么这个呢？再给你们一次机会
everyone, Why is this one no good? Okay,
每一个人,为什么这是一个不好吗?
下面这个有什么错误？
I'm trying to get animals[4] over there, why? Nobody?
我想让动物[4]在那里,为什么?
我尝试获取 animals[4]，为什么，谁要回答？
This one's easier, Array index, yes! Array index is
这个更简单,数组索引,是的!
这个问题比较简单。数组的索引，答得好，再发颗糖
out of bounds because arrays are indexed starting at zero,
界外,因为数组索引从0开始,
数组的索引值越界了，数组是从 0 开始索引的
Okay, so giraffe, cow, doggie, bird that's zero, one, two and
长颈鹿,牛,狗,鸟,是零,一个,两个,
所以 Giraffe，Cow，Doggie，Bird 对应 0，1，2，3
three, So if I say, give me array number four, bam,
三,如果我说,给我4号,砰,
如果我说，把第四个给我
crashed my program array index out of bounds,
我的程序数组下标越界坠毁,
程序就会因为数组索引越界而崩溃
Let's talk about the fact that array is a sequence,
让我们来谈谈数组是一个序列,
下面讲讲数组作为一个 Sequence（序列）的特性
Array is actually a collection and collections are sequences,
数组实际上是一个集合和集合序列,
数组实际上是一个 Collection（集合），而集合又是序列
And a sequence means I can do for in on it, So if I say for
和一个序列意味着我可以做的,如果我说
一个序列意味着我可以对它进行 for...in 循环
animal in animals, my little for loop will get executed
动物在动物身上,我的小for循环将得到执行
如果我说 for animal in animals，这个 for 循环就会执行四次
four times, once with animal being giraffe, next one with
四倍,一旦动物是长颈鹿,下一个
第一次 animal 取值为 Giraffe，第二次
animal being cow, next one with animal being doggie,
动物是牛,下一个动物是小狗,
animal 是 Cow，接下来是 Doggie
next one animal being bird, Okay, so that's a really cool
下一个动物被鸟,好吧,这是一个很酷的
最后一个是 Bird。这真是一个很棒的功能
feature, Remember this is the only for there is in swift,
特性,记住这是唯一在迅速、
记住这是 Swift 中唯一的 for 循环形式
For in, that's the only for there is, nothing else,
中,这是唯一的,没有别的,
for...in 这就是唯一的，没有其他了
So array in a lot of classes and structs
所以在很多类和结构体数组
在数组，以及 iOS 众多类和结构体中
in iOS have some interesting methods
iOS中有一些有趣的方法
有一些有趣的方法
that have arguments that are closures, So I teach closures
闭包有争论,所以我教闭包
它们有闭包类型的参数
to you right at the beginning of the of the quarter,
你在本季度的开始,
所以我在这期课程的开头就先讲了闭包
And why do I do that? Because closures are an important
为什么我这样做?
为什么我要先讲它，因为如果你想把 iOS API 用好
thing to understand if you want to really use iOS API
要理解如果你想真正使用iOS API
就应该先理解闭包这个重要的概念
well, So let's take at this (just so we can learn a little
好吧,让我们在这个(这样我们可以学习一点
我们看看这个（我们从中还可以学到
bit about how closures can make our API great,
闭包可以让我们的API是如何伟大,
如何把我们自己的 API 设计的更好
especially again if you're doing functional programming,
尤其是如果你做函数式编程,
尤其是你要用函数式编程的话
closures can be really good), but why are closures so great?
闭包可以很好),但为什么关闭如此之大?
闭包可以从中起到很大作用），闭包为什么这么有用？
So let's look at this so, this first function right here
让我们看看这,这里的第一个函数
我们看看这些，第一个方法
called filter is an array method,
称为滤波器是一个数组的方法,
叫做 filter，是数组的方法
Nothing special about it, it's just func in array,
没有什么特别之处,只是在数组函数,
它没什么特别的，只是一个数组的方法
It has one argument, which is called includeElement,
它有一个参数,称为includeElement,
它有一个参数，叫做 includeElement
And that argument is a function, It's a function that
参数是一个函数,这个函数
这个参数是一个函数
takes one argument which is of the same type of the things in
需要一个参数是相同类型的东西
这个函数有一个类型与数组元素类型一致的参数
the arrays, cuz it's a t, So I have an array angle bracket t,
数组,因为这是一个t,所以我有一个数组尖括号t,
因为这个类型是 T，所以我有一个 Array
It's a generic type so this function is declared in that
这是一个泛型类型声明这个函数
这是一个泛型，这个函数是
generic type so the t means the same t, the same type, So
泛型类型t意味着相同的,相同的类型
基于这个泛型声明的。所以这个 T 是同一个 T，同一个类型
if I have an array of strings this filter expects this
如果我有一个字符串数组这个过滤器预计
如果我有一个字符串数组，那么 filter 方法的参数
to be a function that takes a string, As its only argument,
是一个函数,它接受一个字符串作为其唯一的参数,
就是一个接收字符串作为唯一参数的函数
And it returns a Bool, so that's the argument,
它返回一个布尔值,这就是论点,
并且这个函数返回一个布尔值
The argument is a function that takes a string and
参数是一个函数,它接受一个字符串
所以 filter 的参数是一个函数，接收字符串
returns a Bool or takes a T, whatever that is, and
返回一个布尔值或T,不管那是什么,和
也就是对应的 T 类型，并返回布尔值
returns a Bool, And then what's the return
返回一个布尔值,然后返回
那么 filter 方法本身
value of this filter thing? It's an array of T, so another
这个过滤器的价值呢?
返回什么东西？返回的是 T 类型元素的数组
array with the same kind of elements, So what does filter
数组具有相同的元素,那么过滤器
是一个与原数组包含同类型元素的新数组
do? Filter takes every single element In the array that
做什么?
filter 有什么用？filter 对数组中的每个元素
you're sending it to and it runs that little function, And
你发送它和它运行这个小函数,和
执行一次传入的函数
if that function returns true, it includes it in the array it
如果这个函数返回true,它包括数组中
如果函数返回 true，就把那个元素包含在返回的数组中
returns, If it returns false it doesn't,
回报,如果它返回false,不,
如果函数返回 false
It throws it out, So
它扔出来,所以
就把那个元素过滤掉（不放入返回数组）
it's a filter: it's filtering your array and creating a new
一个过滤器:它的过滤你的数组和创建一个新的
filter 就是过滤器：它创建一个新数组来过滤原数组
array with all the things you don't want as defined by this
数组定义了所有你不想要的东西
根据作为参数传入的函数来判断
function that you're providing as an argument,
函数,你提供作为参数,
哪些是你不想要的元素
With all the things you don't want thrown out, So for
所有的事情你不要扔掉,所以
把你不想要的元素都过滤掉
example here, I have this var that I'm creating,
例子,我有一个var我创建,
例如：我有一个变量
bigNumbers, and I'm creating an array on the fly 2,
bigNumbers,我创建一个动态数组2,
叫做 bigNumbers，我紧接着创建了一个数组 [2,47,118,5,9]
47,118,5,9, (see? I created an array), and look,
47118、5、9日(见?
（看，我创建了一个数组）
I'm sending it a message right away, Yeah, I didn't have to
我马上发送一条消息,是的,我不需要
我紧接着给数组发送了一个消息
put it into another var, by the way, I could have but,
把它放到另一个var,顺便说一下,我也可以,但
我没必要声明另一个变量，尽管我可以那样做
I just want all be on one line here, I created this array and
我想都有一条线,我创建了这个数组
但是在这里我更希望只用一行代码。我创建了这个数组
I'm sending it the message filter and
我发送消息过滤和
然后给它发送消息 filter
look what I'm providing for the argument there,
我提供的观点看,
仔细看参数这里我写的是什么
That include element it has an underbar, so, you don't have
它有一个下划线,包括元素,所以,你没有
因为 includeElement 的外部参数名有下划线，所以没必要
to actually put the include element column in there, So,
把包括元素列在这里,所以,
真的写上 includeElement 这个参数名
what am I putting in there? That's a closure, So
我将在那里?
所以我在这里填入的是什么？是一个闭包
that means, it's a function, Now, Swift knows that this is
这意味着,这是一个函数,现在,迅速知道这是
这意味着，它是个函数。Swift 知道它
a function that returns a bool, So
一个函数,返回一个布尔值
是个函数，而且会返回布尔值
I don't have to put the word return in there, I can use
我没有把这个词返回,我可以使用
所以我没必要在闭包里加上 return
dollar zero to be the one and only argument to the function,
美元零是唯一的参数函数,
我可以用 $0 代表闭包的第一个也是唯一的一个参数
And I'm just going to check and
和我要检查
我接下来要检查
see if dollar zero is greater than 20, in other words,
看看美元零大于20,换句话说,
$0 是否比 20 大，也就是说
is this a big number, So I get back an array which has only
这是一个巨大的数字,所以我回去只有一个数组
检查它是不是个“大数字”。然后我取得了一个新数组
47 and 118 in it, because I've filtered out all the things
47 - 118,因为我已经过滤掉所有的东西
里面只有 47 和 118，因为我已经把所有
where the value's not greater than 20, Imagine writing
值不大于20,想象写作吗
不满足大于 20 这个条件的数都过滤掉了。想象一下
this line of code without filter, You're gonna have
这行代码没有过滤,你会拥有的
如果不依靠 filter 来实现这行代码
to a for loop, You're gonna have to create another array,
for循环,你需要创建另一个数组,
你可能要写个 for 循环，然后创建一个新数组
You're gonna have to run this little function,
你需要运行这个函数,
然后执行这个小函数
call this function, create a new array and
调用这个函数,创建一个新数组
调用这个函数，创建新数组
add, append thing to do it, It's at least four or
添加,添加的事情,它至少四、
然后把符合条件的加进去
five lines of code, And here you get it in one line of
五行代码,你得到它在一行
至少也要四五行代码。用了 filter，只用一行代码就实现了
code, okay? So you see how closure there has helped us,
代码,好吗?
闭包是如何帮我们实现这个功能的？你们理解了吗
This is also much more readable cuz you can read this
这也是更可读的因为你可以阅读
这也让代码更具可读性
like this: Let the big numbers equal this array, but
是这样的:让大数字等于这个数组,但是
可以这样读：让 bigNumbers 等于这个数组
filter for things there are greater than 20,
过滤的东西有大于20,
但是只要其中比 20 大的
That reads nicely, so I'm just clear,
所以我只是清楚,读好
这样读起来太顺了，表达清晰
It's very easy to understand what's going on here,
很容易理解这是怎么回事,
非常容易让人理解这行代码在做什么
So here's another one, It's called map, What does map do?
这是另一个,它叫地图,地图做什么?
另一个方法，叫做 map，它是做什么的？
It takes a closure, or a function, And
这需要一个闭包,或一个函数
它也接收一个闭包，或者说一个函数
it executes that function in order to transform each
它执行,每个函数为了变换
它会执行那个函数
of the elements in the array you're sending map to,
数组中元素的你发送地图,
将你传入数组的每个元素进行转化
to a new array,
到一个新数组,
然后输出到一个新数组
Now that transformation could be anything that a function
现在转换可以是任何一个函数
这种转化可以是任何形式的，只要通过函数能做到
can do, And you can convert it to any new type you want,
可以做,你可以将它转换成任何你想要的新类型,
甚至可以转化为任何你想要的新类型
Although it's one function, so it
尽管它是一个函数,所以它
但是它是一个函数
coverts everything to the same type, So you could use it for
将相同类型的一切,所以你可以用它来
它只能把所有东西转化为同一个类型
type conversions like I have here, I've taken 1,
类型转换喜欢这里,我已经1
你可以用它来实现类型转化。例如这里
2, 3 and mapped it to the string versions of 1, 2, 3, so
2、3和映射的字符串版本1,2,3,所以
我把数字 1，2，3 映射成字符串形式的 "1"，"2"，"3"
now I have the new array with strings in it, String of 1,
现在我有新的数组与字符串,字符串的
现在我得到了一个新数组，包含字符串的数组 ["1"，"2"，"3"]
string of 2, string of 3, That's a trivial mapping,
字符串的字符串,这是一个简单的映射,
这只是个意义不大的映射
But you can imagine much more powerful mappings where you
但是你可以想象,你更强大的映射
但你可以想象下功能更加强大的映射
take each element of the array, and
把数组的每个元素,
对数组的每个元素
call some complicated function on it, and get the result into
调用一些复杂函数,并得到结果
调用非常复杂的函数，取得结果
a new array, So by creating a really powerful argument there
一个新数组,通过创建一个非常强大的论点
放入新数组。这需要创建一个非常强大的函数作为参数
instead of String($0), something more powerful, you
而不是字符串(0美元),更强大,你
替代 String($0)
can really have one line of code that's really expressive,
真的可以有非常富有表现力的一行代码,
你可以创造出意义丰富的单行代码
It can do a lot of things, One thing about this one: notice
它可以做很多事情,关于这个:注意到一件事
可以做很多事情。注意这个地方
that after the word map, there's no parentheses,
之后,地图,这个词没有括号,
map 的后面没有小括号
no open parentheses, Did you notice that?
没有开括号,你注意了吗?
没有左半小括号，注意到了吗？
You see the difference between filter and map, okay?
你看到过滤和地图之间的区别,好吗?
你们是否注意到了 filter 和 map 的区别
When I called filter, I said open parentheses,
我叫过滤器时,我说的开括号,
当我调用 filter 时，我在后面写了个小括号
open curly brace, the function, curly brace, close
花括号,函数、花括号结束
然后是大括号，函数，大括号结束，小括号结束
parentheses, Here I just say, , no parentheses,
括号,在这里,我只是说,,没有括号,
但是 map 这里，我只是用了 ，没有小括号
And this is what's called the trailing closure syntax, You
这就是所谓的后关闭语法,你
这种语法叫做尾随闭包
are allowed to have closures that are the last argument to
允许有关闭最后一个参数
当闭包作为最后一个参数时
a function, The outside of the parentheses of that function,
一个函数,这个函数的括号外的,
你可以把闭包放到函数的参数部分的括号的外边
if they're trailing, see they're trailing the call, And
如果他们落后,看到他们落后于电话,
如果是尾随闭包，它们跟在函数调用的尾部
in fact, if there's only one argument and
事实上,如果只有一个参数,
实际上，如果只有一个参数
it's closure, you don't need the parentheses at all,
它关闭,您不需要括号,
并且这个参数是闭包，连小括号都不需要了
And that's what happened there with map,
这是发生了什么有地图,
这种情形就是 map 这行代码这样
I'm just saying map, parentheses get rid of them,
我只是说地图,括号去掉,
只是说 map，省略了小括号
Just put the closure there, trailing, And
把闭包,拖着,
把闭包跟在后面
that also results in some pretty cool looking
这也导致一些很酷
产生了像这行代码一样的很酷的效果
code right here, you see that? So you can use that anywhere
代码在这里,你看到了吗?
你们理解了吗？你们可以在任何地方
that a closure is the last argument of function,
闭包是最后一个参数的函数,
用这个语法，只要最后一个参数是函数
You can take it outside, just put the curly braces, Cuz you already
你可以把它外面,只是把花括号,因为你已经
你可以把闭包从小括号中提出来，只留下大括号这部分
got the curly braces, and that's why they do it,
花括号,这就是为什么他们这样做,
因为已经有大括号扩起来了，所以语法允许
You don't really need the parentheses around it as well,
你真的不需要括号围绕它,
周围的小括号也不需要了
So put that at the end,
所以最后,
把闭包直接放在尾部
And put all the rest of the arguments, if you had them,
并把所有剩下的参数,如果你有他们,
如果有其他参数的话
inside the parentheses right before, This last one, I won't
在括号之前,最后一个,我不会
仍然把它们放在小括号内。最后一个
go into the details, but it's a similar kind of thing,
进入细节,但它是一个类似的事情,
我不会深入讲解，不过这个和前面的 map 是类似的
Reduce: what reduce does is it takes an entire array and
减少:降低是整个数组
reduce，它的功能是将整个数组
reduces it to a single value, So here I'm reducing it by
减少到一个单一值,所以这里我减少了
变成一个值，这里我把
adding all the numbers in the array up, So my closure is $0
数组中所有的数字加到一起,所以我关闭0美元
整个数组的数字都加起来，闭包写作 $0 + $1
+ $1, because the argument it takes is a function that takes
+ 1美元,因为所需的参数是一个函数
因为这个参数是有两个参数的函数
two elements, One of them is an element from the array and
两个元素,其中一个是一个元素的数组
其中一个是数组中的一个元素
the other is the answer so far, and
另一个答案是到目前为止,
另一个是目前为止累计的结果
then it returns the new answer so far, So it just executes
然后它返回新的答案为止,所以它只是执行
然后它返回新的结果
that function over and over and over on the arrays,
这个函数数组一遍又一遍又一遍,
所以 reduce 对数组不断地执行这个函数
By the way, notice that I can say this as sum = [1,
顺便说一下,请注意,我可以说这是金额=[1,
注意到了吗，我也可以写成 let sum = [1,2,3].reduce(0, +)
2, 3],reduce(0, +) which is my starting so far value,
2、3),减少(0,+)这是我开始到目前为止,
0 代表初始的迭代值
Which I haven't added a name on, so it starts at 0 and
我没有添加一个名称,它从0开始,
它没有参数名，所以会从零开始
then I can say plus, The reason I can say plus right
然后我可以加上说,我可以说+正确的原因
然后我可以只写个加号，最下面这行代码
there at the bottom line, is because plus
在底线,是因为+
可以直接写个加号的原因是
in Swift is not some kinda weird built-in thing,
在斯威夫特不是内置一些有点奇怪的事情,
加号在 Swift 中不是什么特殊的内置的符号
it's just a function, It's a function that happens to be
它只是一个函数,这个函数会发生
它仅仅是个函数。是这样一个函数
declared in a way that says, this is a function, but
宣布在某种程度上说,这是一个函数,但是
它是这样声明的，这是个函数
it's two arguments it's going either side of it,
这是两个参数的任何一方,
它的两个参数就是加号两侧的值
It's called an infix operator on a function, So
它叫做中缀操作符在一个函数,所以
这叫做 infix（中缀）操作符函数
since plus is just a function, and
因为加是一个函数,和
因为 + 是个函数
I'm taking a function as an argument,
我把一个函数作为参数,
我把一个函数作为这里的参数
as long as it's a function that takes two arguments and
只要一个函数有两个参数
因为它是一个接收两个参数
returns one, which is exactly what plus does, it works
返回一个,这正是+,它的工作原理
返回一个值的函数，就和加法运算是一致的
there, We could have done that in our calculator brain, too,
在那里,我们可以做我们的计算器的大脑,也
所以它可以用在这里，也可以用在 CalculatorBrain 中
Remember all that closures we were doing ($0* $1),
记得关闭所有我们所做的(0 * 1美元),
还记得那些形如 $0 * $1 的闭包吗
that could've just been *), ($0+$1), that could've just
刚才*),(0 + 1美元),刚刚
它可以被简化为 *，$0 + $1 可以被简化为 +
been +, Cuz + is a function that takes two doubles and
+,因为+是一个函数,它接受两个双打
因为 + 是一个函数，接收两个 Double 作为参数
returns a double, Plus also know how to plus other types,
返回一个双,加上也知道如何加上其他类型,
返回一个 Double，+ 也懂得怎么操作其他类型
ints, And it even knows how to plus and into a float,
整数,甚至知道如何加到一个浮点数,
比如 Int，Float 也可以
for example, etc, You can plus strings together,
例如,等等,你可以加上字符串连接起来,
你还可以对两个 String 相加
So that was just a little aside just to give you
这只是一个小一边给你
再说就有点远了，这里只做简单的介绍
an introduction there, You're gonna start seeing a lot of
介绍,你会开始看到很多
你还会看到很多方法
methods that take functions as arguments,
将函数作为参数的方法,
它们的参数是有两个参数的函数
So I want you to start to get comfortable with that,
所以我希望你开始熟悉,
我希望你们逐渐适应这种方式
Okay, dictionary, So we learned a lot about dictionary
好的,字典,我们学到了很多关于词典
好了，下面讲 Dictionary（字典）。在第一讲中
in our first lecture, Dictionary also has this
在我们的第一节课,字典也有这个
我们已经学了不少有关字典的知识了
special declaration syntax, which is open square bracket
特别声明的语法,这是开放的方括号
字典也有这种特殊的声明语法
key type colon value type closed square bracket, So
密钥类型结肠值类型闭方括号,
左半方括号，键类型，冒号，值类型，右半方括号
those two things in yellow are equivalent,
这两件事在黄色是等价的,
所以两个标注为黄色的部分是等价的
And the one on the bottom seems to be the preferred
和一个在底部似乎是首选
目前第二个好像更受欢迎一些
one these days, So you know you can create a dictionary,
这些天,所以你知道你可以创建一个字典,
你们已经知道了能创建一个字典
By the way, I show you creating dictionaries from
顺便说一下,我给你创建字典
我这里展示的是如何通过常量
kind of constant values here,
类型的常量值,
来创建一个字典
But you can create a dictionary just by saying,
但是你可以创建一个字典就说,
但是你也可以先创建空字典
let d equal dictionary, Open parenthesis,
让d等于字典,左括号,
比如 let d = [String:Int]()
close parenthesis, And if you say var d
关闭括号,如果你说var d
或者是创建可变的字典的变量
equals dictionary, then now you can start appending items
等于字典,那么现在你就可以开始添加项目
比如 var d = [String:Int]()
onto it because you get an empty dictionary to start, But
到它,因为你会得到一个空的字典开始,但是
可以之后再往里面加东西
here I'm starting my dictionary with stuff in it,
在这里我对东西,开始我的字典
这里我初始化字典时就包含了一些内容
That probably should say var pac12teamRankings
应该说var pac12teamRankings
这里应该用 var pac12teamRankings 而不是 let
because two lines later I say pac12teamRankings sub Cal
因为两条线后,我说pac12teamRankings子卡尔
因为隔了两行代码之后
equals 12, Note also that
等于12,也要注意
我用了 pac12teamRankings["Cal"] = 12
when I try to get the ranking of Ohio State, it returns nil,
当我试图让俄亥俄州立大学的排名,它返回nil,
另外注意我尝试获取键为 "Ohio State" 的值，返回的是 nil
And we know that when we use square brackets to get
我们知道,当我们使用方括号
我们知道当用方括号
something out of the dictionary, it returns
的字典,它返回
在字典中查询某个键时
an optional of our value type, Our value type here is ints,
一个可选值类型,我们的价值类型是整数,
返回的是值类型的可选类型，这里我们的值类型是 Int
so it's gonna return an optional int,
所以它会返回一个可选的整型,
所以返回的是 Int?
Alright, enumeration, A dictionary is also
好的,枚举,字典也
下面是字典的枚举。字典也是一个 Collection
a collection and thus can be sequenced, So you can do for
一个集合,因此可以排序,所以你可以做
因此也是 Sequence，所以可以用 for...in 循环
in on it, Of course, a dictionary has keys and
在,当然,钥匙和一本字典
字典包含键和值
values, So we need a tuple to do our enumeration for
值,所以我们需要一个元组的枚举
所以我们要用一个元组来枚举
the tuple key common value in the dictionary, And
元组密钥共同价值在字典里,
写作 for (key, value) in dictionary
then it'll go through and key in value will be set,
然后它会通过键的值将被设置,
然后这个循环就开始了，会遍历所有的键值对
It's a perfectly straightforward way
这是一个非常简单的方法
用这种方式对字典进行枚举或迭代
to enumerate or iterate over a dictionary, Okay,
列举或遍历一个字典,
很完美，而且容易书写
String, So string, you would think, is the simplest class
字符串,字符串,你可能会认为,是最简单的类
String，你可能会认为
in all of any language, It's just a string, right?
在所有的任何语言,它只是一个字符串,对吧?
String 是所有编程语言中最简单的类，它仅仅是个字符串
Well, that turns out not to be so true, When you think of
嗯,这结果不是那么真实的,当你想到
但是这种想法可能不那么正确
a string that represents every language in the entire world,
一个字符串,该字符串代表整个世界上每一种语言,
想象一下当一个字符串可以表达世界上所有语言的时候
all of a sudden it got real complicated real fast,
突然它有真实的复杂真实的快,
它突然间就变得复杂了
Because some languages are ideographic, Some languages go
因为有些语言表意的,一些语言
因为一些语言是表意的
right to left instead of left to right, Some languages have
右到左左到右,而是一些语言
还有一些语言是从右往左书写的
a lot of diacritic marks and accents in them, Some don't,
大量的可区别的标志和口音,有些不
一些语言有很多变音符或重音符，而另外一些没有
Most languages don't use the same alphabet as we use,
大多数语言不使用我们使用相同的字母,
绝大多数语言和我们用的字母表不一样
So string is super complicated,
字符串是超级复杂,
所以字符串其实非常复杂
this is a very complicated class, Now string tries
这是一个非常复杂的类,现在尝试字符串
这是一个非常复杂的类
its best and does a pretty good job of simplifying it for
最好的,也很好地简化它
String 尽其所能让我们操作字符串变得容易
your use, But the complexity is still there, Now the most
使用,但仍然存在的复杂性,现在最多
但是复杂性还是存在的
important complexity about a string is that representing
重要的复杂性是一个字符串表示
String 最复杂的是
a string is not always one character equals one
一个字符串并不总是一个字符等于1
显示的每一个字符
internal representation unit, Now the units, the kind of
内部表示单位,现在的单位,这样的
并不是都能用一个字节表示的
thing that's used to represent strings on the inside,
用于表示的字符串,
String 内部用来表达一个字符串的编码
are Unicodes, I had you skip that reading in assignment
unicode,我如果你跳过阅读作业
叫做 Unicode。在作业一中，我让你们跳过阅读这部分
one, I'm putting it in for assignment two,
一个,我把它转让两个,
现在我把这部分放在了作业二中
It's really not that critical that you understand it,
这真的不是,关键你理解它,
理解这部分内容并没有那么重要
I think it's very interesting, though, so
不过,我认为这是非常有趣的
但是我觉得这是个很有趣的东西
you probably want to read it, But the thing about Unicodes
你可能想要读它,但关于unicode
所以你可能愿意去阅读这些
is it's not one Unicode equals one character,
它不是一个Unicode等于一个字符,
Unicode 的一个特点是，一个 Unicode 不等价于一个字符
In fact, if you have like a little emoji of a dog barking,
事实上,如果你像一个小emoji狗狂吠,
比如有一个类似狗叫的表情
that might be three Unicode characters, It's only one with
这可能是三个Unicode字符,它只有一个
它很可能是由三个 Unicode 字符表达的
regards to what you perceive to be a character, Or
问候你的感知是一个字符,或者
但看起来，它就是一个字符
even more simply, the example I have here, the word cafe,
更简单,我这里的例子中,这个词的咖啡馆,
来看个更简单的例子，café 这个单词
It's got e accent aigu on the end, right, it's a French
它有e口音aigu结束,对的,这是一个法国人
它的结尾有个闭音符，它是一个法语词
word, e accent aigu, That could be four Unicodes,
e口音aigu词,可以四个unicode,
以 é 结尾。这个词可能是由 4 个 Unicode 构成的
because there is a Unicode for e accent aigu,
因为有一个Unicode e口音aigu,
有一个单独的 Unicode 代表 é
Or it could be five, It could be the e with another Unicode
也可以是五个,可以是与另一个Unicode e
也有可能是由 5 个 Unicode 构成的。可能是 e 加上另一个
character that says put an accent on that previous
性格说给之前的口音
表达“给前面那个字符加上闭音符”这样含义的 Unicode
character, So, when you have this kind of unknown how many
性格,所以,当你有这种未知的多少
当你不知道到底有多少字符来表达它的时候
characters it represents, you need a new abstraction
它所代表人物,你需要一个新的抽象
你需要一个新的抽象概念
to represent what we perceive as humans to be a character,
来表示我们认为人类是一个字符,
来表达我们人类认知上的字符
Even that is difficult to truly define, when you think
即使是很难真正定义,当你的想法
要针对世界上所有语言，定义出这种抽象概念非常困难
of all the languages in the world, It's easy in English,
世界上所有的语言,英语很容易,
只是针对英语的话很简单
though, So that's really how we're gonna interact with
不过,这就是我们如何相互作用
这就是我们使用 String 的方法
strings: to try to think of them in terms of characters,
字符串:试图把他们的角色,
把它视作一串人类认知上的字符
But a string itself is not actually
但一个字符串本身不是
但是 String 本身并不是
a collection of characters,
字符的集合,
单纯的字符的集合
A string is a more powerful internal structure,
一个字符串是一个更强大的内部结构,
String 是一个内部非常强大的结构体
it's got all the Unicodes in there and all that stuff,
它有所有的unicode和所有的东西,
它包含了一串字符中所有的 Unicode 和其他东西
it's not quite that, And that makes for a little bit of
不是,这让一点
和你想象的不太一样
complication as you're gonna see, Now, you can't; String is
并发症你会看到,现在,你不能,字符串
因此在使用 String 的时候还有其它不便之处
indexable which means you can use the open square brackets
可转位,这意味着您可以使用方括号
虽然 String 可以用类似索引数组的形式
just like you can in array to get one of the characters,
就像你可以在数组的一个字符,
通过方括号取得字符串中的某个字符
The only rub is what I said on the other slide that index
唯一的摩擦是我说什么其他指数的下滑
我之前提到过会带来的麻烦是
is not an int, So if you have the word hello,
不是一个整数,所以如果你有你好,这个词
String 的索引不是一个 Int 类型。你有一个单词 hello
it's not like you can say, hello[1] equals e,
它不像你可以说,你好[1]= e,
你没法通过类似 hello[1] 的方式来取得字符 e
You can't do it that way because it might,
你不能这么做,因为这可能会,
你没法那样做，因为可能有这种情况
if it was cafe then cafe sub 3,
如果是咖啡馆,咖啡馆下标3,
如果这个单词是 café，然后取 café[3]
It's not clear, You want a character at that point
不清楚,你想要一个字符
String 并不清楚你想要的是第四个字节还是整个字符
so you've got to make sure you get the right index in there
所以你要确保你得到正确的索引
同时你还要确保自己提供的了正确的索引
because that index behind the scenes can be quite
因为这幕后指数可以相当
因为这个索引位置的背后，实际上非常复杂
complicated, There's this other struct for it, which is
复杂,这里有其他结构,这是
因此产生了另外一个结构体，叫做 String.Index
called a String,Index, So let's say I had a string,
叫一个字符串,指数,假设我有一个字符串,
我有一个字符串
which I'm gonna call s and I'm gonna put hello into there,
我将称之为年代和我要把你好,
命名为 s，然后我把 "hello" 赋值给它
Now, what if I wanted s[0] now, I can't do s[0],
现在,如果我想要s[0]现在,我不能做[0],
现在，我要取得 s[0]，当然没法写作 s[0]
because we don't index strings by integers but
因为我们不指数字符串,整数
因为没法通过整数来索引字符串
let's say I want that, How do I get it? Well,
假设我希望这样,我怎么得到它?
我要那个字符，到底怎么拿到它？
I start by calling this var, again using this var and
我又开始通过调用这个变量,使用这个变量
首先我操作 s，调用 s.startIndex
string called startIndex, okay? It gives us
为被称作startIndex的字符串?
它返回给我一个 String.Index 类型的值
a string,index, It's very important, we need to get
一个字符串,索引,这是非常重要的,我们需要得到的
下面很关键，我们需要一个变量保存这个 String.Index
a hold of a string,index because the way we're gonna
的一个字符串,指数,因为我们要的方式
因为我们接下来要在字符串中
move around in string is by taking index we know and
在字符串是我们知道,通过索引
以这个已知的索引为基准
moving forward or backward by character, by human
向前或向后通过角色,人类
以人类认知的字符为单位向前或者向后移动
understandable character, Not by Unicodes, because we
可以理解的字符,而不是unicode,因为我们
不是以 Unicode 为单位
don't know how many Unicodes there are per character but
不知道有多少unicode每个字符
因为我们不知道每个字符到底用了几个 Unicode 来表达
by character, we're gonna be moving back and forth,
的性格,我们会来回移动,
我们只根据字符来前后移动
So we start with this first one,
因此,我们从第一个开始,
所以我们从第一个开始
And so now I can create a variable firstChar which is of
所以现在我可以创建一个变量firstChar的
现在我创建一个变量叫做 firstChar
this type Character,
这种性格,
它是 Character 类型的
that human understandable character,
人类可以理解的性格,
是人类认知上的字符
That's gonna be equal s[firstIndex], So see look,
会平等年代firstIndex,看看看,
它将被赋值成 s[firstIndex]
I've used square brackets to index into a string, but
我使用了方括号索引到一个字符串,但是
看，这里我用了方括号来索引字符串
I had to use a String,Index not an Int, This first index
我必须使用一个字符串,指数不是一个Int,第一个索引
我必须用 String.Index 而不是 Int 类型
I got by asking the string "what's your first index"?
我问了字符串“第一指数”是什么?
我得到字符串的第一个索引，还要先问它才行
Well this is kinda useless because I have to ask
这是无用的,因为我要问
这个步骤感觉挺多余的
the string, what's the index of your first character and
字符串的第一个字符的索引
我先向字符串索要它的第一个字符的索引之后
then turn around say okay give me S of your first character,
然后转身说好的给我的你的第一个字符,
然后又说“好吧，我实际上要的是你的第一个字符”
So that's not the interesting thing,
这不是有趣的,
这种方式一点也不有趣
what if I want the next character, If I
如果我想要下一个字符,如果我
如果我要下一个字符呢?
want the next character, I ask the string what's the index of
希望下一个字符,我问字符串的索引
如果我要下一个字符，我要对字符串说
the character after your first character, And
后你的第一个字符,
“你的第一个字符之后的字符的索引是什么”
it'll give me a new index, of its second character and
它会给我一个新的索引,第二个字符和
它会给我一个新的索引，即它第二个字符的索引
now I can get that one, Even that is a little bit like,
现在我可以得到一个,甚至有点像,
这样我才能拿到第二个字符。这种感觉就像是
my God, you're kidding me,
我的上帝,你在跟我开玩笑,
大地母亲在忽悠着我
this is really how I have to do this? What if I wanted
这真的是我必须这样做吗?
我真的只能这么做吗?
to go jump ahead though, and get the fourth, the fifth
去跳过,第四,第五
我想跳过前面的字符，直接取得第四个，第五个怎么办？
character, let's say? Well I can jump ahead by saying s,
的性格,让我们说什么?
我们要这样做：对字符串 s 说
give me the index of, starting at your first index,
给我的指数,开始你的第一个索引,
“从你的第一个索引开始”
that's four ahead so jump four ahead,
提前4所以跳四之前,
因为要跳到第四个，所以“往前跳四下”
four characters ahead, This is all a little
四个字符,这是一点
这样它就前进了四个字符
tedious and of course this is not the actual way that we're
乏味的,当然这不是我们实际的方式
这实在够无聊的，当然这不是我们和 String 打交道的常见方式
interacting with strings, We're usually looking for
与字符串交互,我们通常寻找
我们常用的是寻找子串
substrings, okay, or subranges of characters or
子字符串,或字符或附属的区域
或者子串所处的位置
we're trying to find a character in a string,
我们试图找到一个字符在字符串中,
或者寻找一个字符串中是否存在某个字符
By the way, you can use ranges, so I could say
顺便说一下,您可以使用范围,所以我可以说
顺便，在这里你可以用 Range，所以可以说
give me the substring which is firstIndex,,,secondIndex and
给我substring firstIndex,,,secondIndex和
给我 firstIndex...secondIndex 区间的子串
it would give me he, A new string which is he, so
他会给我,他是一个新字符串,因此
这样它会返回我 "he"。一个新字符串 "he"
you can use ranges there but they have to be string,index
您可以使用范围,但它们必须是字符串,指数
所以这里你可以用 Range，但必须是 String.Index 类型的
not ints, So we want basically something that
不是整数,所以基本上我们想要的东西
而不是 Int 类型的。所以我们更希望的是
is a collection of characters, A string is not a collection
是一个字符的集合,一个字符串不是一个收集
操作一串字符的集合。String 不是字符的集合
of characters so you can't do for in, for example, on it,
的人物所以你不能做的,例如,,
所以你没法对它用 for...in 遍历
You can't even say index(of:),
你甚至不能说指数(的),
你也没法对它用 index(of:) 方法
index(of:) is this great thing where you can,
:指数(),这是好事,你可以
index(of:) 对于一个集合而言非常好用
if you have a collection of things, you can say give
如果你有收藏的东西,你可以说
你可以说
me this index of this thing in there, You can't even do that
我这个指数的这个东西,你甚至不能这样做
把这个元素的索引找出来
with a string because it's not a collection, Luckily,
一个字符串,因为它不是一个收集,幸运的是,
但是你没法对 String 这样做，因为它不是 Collection
string has a var which will give you a collection of its
字符串有一个var,会给你一个收集的
幸运的是，String 有一个变量
characters, And not only is it gonna give
字符,它不仅是要给
不仅返回给你一个它包含的字符的集合
you a collection of its characters that you can for
你的角色,你可以集合
你还可以对这个字符集合用
in over and do index(of:), but the string indexes you get
:在做指数(),但是字符串的索引
for...in 循环，或者调用 index(of:)，而且你通过这个集合
from that collection will match what's in the string, So
从这个集合将匹配的字符串,所以
索引到的字符和字符串中实际包含的字符是匹配的
you can use this collection of characters to find things in
您可以使用此字符找到事物的集合
所以你可以用这个字符集合来查找字符
there, get the index of a character, things like
在那里,得到字符的索引,之类的东西
或者取得某个字符的索引，等等
that, And then use the indexes you find there to go back to
你,然后使用索引找到回到
然后拿着你找到的索引，对原字符串说
your string and say, okay now give me a substring, So
你的字符串说,现在给我一个字符串,所以
现在给我一个指定的子串
characters is the name of this var on string, So for example,
人物的名字是var在字符串,例如,
String 下的这个变量名字叫做 characters
if I want to iterate over all the characters one by one,
如果我想要遍历所有的人物一个接一个地
举例来说，如果我要所有的字符，一个挨一个
do a for loop over them I can say, for c:,
做一个for循环在我可以说,c:,
用 for 循环遍历它们，我可以这样说
which will be of type character,
将字符类型,
for c: Character in s.characters
by the way, in s,characters, I can't say for c: in s, for
顺便说一下,在年代,字符,我不能说对c:在年代
我不能说 for c in s
c: in s,characters, And that's just gonna call my for
c:在年代,字符,就打电话给我
必须说 for c in s.characters
loop once with each character, Question? Yeah,
与每个字符循环一次,问题吗?
这样就能通过 for 循环变量遍历每一个字符了。有什么问题？
great question, So if I do this over cafe,
很好的问题,如果我在咖啡屋,
问得好！如果我对 café 做 for 循环
what am I gonna get? I'm gonna get four characters, okay,
我会得到什么?
我会得到什么？我会得到四个字符
because that E-accent-agu that they use is considered in our
因为这E-accent-agu他们使用被认为是在我们的
因为 é 被视作
human perception one character,
人类感知一个字符,
一个人类认知中的字符
I'll get four characters, So there is a character,
我将得到四个字符,所以有一个角色,
我会得到四个字符，有一个 Character
Characters are struct, right? And in the character
字符结构,对吧?
Character 是结构体，Character 中刚好
there is a character that represents e-accent-agu,
有一个字符代表e-accent-agu,
有一个能代表 é
No matter how it's represented in the string,
无论如何用字符串表示,
不论它在 String 内部是怎么表达的
in the string it might be two characters, it might be one,
这可能是两个字符的字符串,它可能是一个,
也许是两个字符，也许是一个
it doesn't matter, You're gonna get the one character
没关系,你会得到一个字符
都没有关系。因为你得到的是一个能代表它的 Character
for it, so that's a really good question, How would I
,这是一个很好的问题,我怎么
这个问题问得好
know how many characters there are in a string? Again,
知道有多少字符在字符串吗?
我怎么才能知道到底一个字符串中有多少字符？
from the user perspective, s,characters,count,
从用户的角度来看,年代,字符,统计,
人类认知的字符。s.characters.count
not s,length or something, s,characters,count,
年代,长度,年代,字符,统计,
不是 s.length 或者其他什么，就是 s.characters.count
the count of the characters in the collection of characters
数的字符集合的字符
意思是在这个字符串的字符集合中，元素的数量
for this string, Also, what if I want to find the first space
对于这个字符串,另外,如果我想找到第一个空间
那么如果我要找字符串中的第一个空格怎么做？
in a string? Got a string with a bunch of words, I wanna find
在一个字符串?
有个字符串，它包含很多单词
the first space, I would say s,characters,index(of: " "),
第一个空间,我想说的年代,字符,指数(:" "),
我要找第一个空格。我应该用 s.characters.index(of: " ")
And that's giving me a string,index(of: " ") that
这是给我一个字符串,指数:" ")
这会返回给我空格在字符集合中的索引
collection of characters, I can then use that string in
的字符集合,然后我可以使用字符串
然后我可以利用这个索引
that index though to go back to my string and do something,
指数虽然回到我的字符串和做一些事情,
回到原字符串中做些什么事情
Maybe insert something there or
也许插入或东西
比如插入一些新字符
delete the word that's right after the space or insert
后删除这个词对空间或插入
删除空格之后的那个单词
another space, I'll have the index into the string now,
另一个空间,现在我要索引的字符串,
或者插入另外一个空格。总之，我将会得到字符串的索引
String is a value type, so when you do let versus var,
字符串是值类型,所以当你让与var,
String 是一个值类型，来对比下用 let 或 var 声明时的不同
if you do let you cannot do things like append on to
如果你让你不能添加
如果你用 let 声明，就没法做类似于 append 之类的操作
the string cuz it's immutable, Most strings in Swift
字符串因为它是不可变的,最迅速的字符串
因为它是不可变的，Swift 中绝大多数字符串都是不可变的
are immutable, that makes it super high performance,
是不可变的,这使得它超高性能,
这使得它效率非常高
But if you have a var you can do greeting plus equals there
但是如果你有一个var你可以问候+ =
但是如果你用 var 声明 greeting，可以 greeting += " there"
and so I can have hello there, It doesn't have any effect on
所以我可以有你好,它没有任何影响
然后得到字符串 "hello there"。这种操作不会改变 hello
hello, the let one because that's immutable, right? Okay,
你好,让一个因为那是不可变的,对吧?
因为 hello 是 let 声明的，不可变，明白了吗？
so I can't do that, And I can use the characters to
所以我不能这样做,我可以使用字符
所以我没法对 hello 做类似的操作。我还可以通过 characters
manipulate strings in really powerful ways, I can, I don't
操纵字符串以真正强大的方式,我可以,我不喜欢
对字符串做出一些更强大的操作
have time to talk about all of it, this is where you really
有时间去谈论它,这是真的吗
我没时间讲解所有字符串操作相关的内容
do need to read your reading assignment carefully, But for
需要仔细阅读你的阅读作业,但对吗
剩下的部分需要你们课后认真阅读
example if I want to insert the word you into hello there,
如果我想插入这个词你你好,
我就讲一个例子，如果我要在 hello 和 there 中间
so it says hello you there, okay, I would just get the,
所以说你好你在那里,好吧,我就会,
插入一个单词 you 变成 hello you there
find the first space by doing characters,index(of: " "),
找到第一个空间通过字符,指数:" "),
我要先通过 characters.index(of: " ") 找到第一个空格
which I showed you on the previous slide, Then there's
我给你上一张幻灯片,还有吗
这个用法上一页我已经展示了
a method in string called, insert the constant,
方法在弦,插入常数,
然后 String 有个方法叫做 insert(contentsOf:at:)
the content of this collection of characters
这个集合的字符的内容
这个方法可以在指定的位置插入复数字符构成的集合
at this location, this string,index, So, when I want
在这个位置,这个字符串索引,所以,当我想要的
指定的位置是 String.Index 类型
a collection of characters that represents " you", I say,
字符的集合,表示“你”,我说,
我要插入代表 " you" 的字符集合
" you",characters, because it's the ,characters, and
“你”,字符,因为它是,人物,和
所以这个应该写作 " you".characters
it gives me a collection of characters for that string, So
它给了我一个字符串的字符集合,
因为 .characters 是 " you" 对应的字符集合
it seems a little weird but It actually turns out to work out
似乎有点奇怪,但实际上
这用法好像有点奇怪，但它确实能达到我要的结果
pretty well, And there's a billion other functions,
很好,十亿其他功能,
Swift 中还有非常多的函数
in Swift, many, many, many,
在迅速,许多,许多,许多,
非常，非常，非常多
I can't talk about them all,
我不能谈论他们所有人,
我没法每个都讲
Notice I say if let firstSpace, because that might
注意我说如果让firstSpace,因为这可能
注意到这里我用了 if let firstSpace，因为有可能
return nil if it couldn't find it, So I wouldn't do it there,
返回nil如果找不到它,所以我不会这样做,
没找到指定的内容，返回 nil 就不执行大括号内的代码
I wouldn't insert it there, Yeah a bunch of other things
我不会插入它,对很多其他的事情
也就不会对原字符串进行插入操作。这里还有一大堆其他方法
checking where strings have prefixes or not,
检查字符串是否前缀,
这个方法可以检查字符串是否包含某个前缀
You can replace subrange, of course you have to find
你可以替换子范围,当然你必须找到
你可以替换子串，当然替换之前
the range which usually you're gonna have to look at that
范围通常你需要看一下
你通常要通过访问字符串的字符集合
collection of characters to find the ranges you wanna
的字符来找到你想要的范围
来确定要替换的范围
replace things etc, Even cool methods like components
取代旧事物等,甚至冷却方法等组件
更有趣的一个方法，你可以通过 components(separatedBy:)
separated by string will take a string that has like comma or
隔开的字符串将会像逗号或一个字符串
对包含逗号或者其他分隔字符的字符串
separated values and grab all of the values and
价值观和抓住所有的价值观和分离
拆分得到所有子串
put them in an array which is kinda fun, Okay so
把它们放在一个数组是有点好玩,所以
然后返回一个包含这些子串的数组
a lot: string has dozens and dozens of methods, you really
有数十种方法很多:字符串,你真的
讲了这么多，String 还有很多很多方法
need to familiarize yourself, If you don't take the time to
需要熟悉,如果你不花时间去
你需要去熟悉它们
familiarize yourself with those thing in strings,
熟悉这些的字符串,
如果你不在这上面花时间的话
Then I guarantee you're going to be writing a program and
我保证你会写一个程序,
我保证有一天你会遇到这种情况，你在写一个程序的时候
you're going to want to do some string parsing or
你会想要做一些解析或字符串
需要对字符串进行解析或其他某种操作
something and you're going to write a whole bunch of
,你要写一大堆
你写了一大段代码来完成这个功能
code to do it and then find out there was one method that
代码,然后发现有一个方法
然后发现其实只要一个原生的方法
did exactly what you want in the string,
做什么你想要的字符串,
就能实现你想要的功能
There are things in there take closures and
有些事情把闭包
有些方法会接收闭包
do all kinds of fun stuff so
这样做各种各样有趣的东西吗
然后做各种有趣的操作
make sure you pay attention to both to string and
一定要注意字符串和
所以你要同时留意 String
to the character view which is a collection of characters,
的角色视图是一个字符的集合,
和 String.CharacterView，也就是字符的集合
All right, other classes, This is kind of quick summary here
好了,其他的类,这是一种快速总结
of other important classes, One is NSObject, NSObject is
其他重要的类,一个是NSObject,NSObject
a class, It is the root of all Objective-C classes, An iOS
一个类,它是所有objective - c类的根源,一个iOS
app written before a couple years ago when Swift came out,
应用程序编写前几年前迅速出来时,
all the classes in there would inherit eventually from
最终所有的类继承
NSObject, So NSObject has a base functionality, You do not
NSObject,所以NSObject基地功能,你不
need to subclass from NSObject to make a swift class,
需要从NSObject子类迅速类,
However there are some really obscure features still left in
然而有一些真的仍在模糊特性
IOS where to expecting a class that inherit from NSObject,
IOS在期待一个继承NSObject类,
If we even get to them, I'll show them to you, They're
如果我们甚至他们,我会告诉他们,他们
pretty rare, But that's just so you know what NSObject is,
非常罕见,但这只是你知道NSObject是什么,
Doesn't really have meaning to you,
并没有真正对你有意义,
cuz you guys are gonna be Swift programmers,
因为你们会迅速程序员,
NSNumber is another class, it's a generic number
NSNumber是另一个类,它是一个通用的数字
holder, This is also inherited from Objective-C, you can tell
从objective - c持有者,这也是继承了,你可以告诉
by the NS there, Until we can hold any kind of number,
通过NS,直到我们可以保存任何类型的号码,
floating point, decimal, you can even hold a bool,
浮点小数,你甚至可以举办一个bool,
since it considers that a number where zero is false and
因为它认为一个零是错误的和的数量
one is true, Any nonzero is true, And you can also
一个是真的,任何非零是真的,你也可以
do type conversions, Again, in swift, we're gonna be using
做类型转换,迅速,我们将会使用吗
the actual concrete number classes like double an int and
实际的混凝土类双int和数量
we'll use their constructors, To do type conversion,
我们将使用构造函数,类型转换,
But just so that you know that NSNumber is around, Okay,
但是这样你知道NSNumber了,好吧,
date, Super important class, Anytime you are representing
日期,超级重要的类,只要你代表
a date or time, you're gonna wanna use this date struct,
一个日期或时间,你要想用这个日期结构,
And it has a lot of ancillary classes that go with it,
和它有很多辅助类,
like calendar, date formatter, date components like date
就像日历,日期格式化程序,组件(比如日期
components will tell you the month of a date, And
组件将告诉你日期,和
of course, what the month of is of a date depends on
当然,月是什么日期取决于
the calendar it's in, cuz not everyone uses a calendar like
日历的,因为不是每个人都使用一个日历
we do, All right, there's a lot of calendars
我们所做的,有很多的日历
all over the Earth that are different than ours,
所有在地球和我们的不同,
So anytime you're even contemplating putting a date
所以任何时候你甚至考虑把一个日期
anywhere in your UI you need to be using this class,
在UI需要使用这个类,
Because if you wanna have your app work in anything but
因为如果你想要你的应用在除了工作
English, you're gonna have to format your date, using
英语,你要格式化日期,使用
the DateFormatter, in whatever locale your app is running in,
dateformat,无论地区应用程序在运行,
So date is super important, You would think date is really
所以日期是非常重要的,你可能会认为是真的
easy, but no, Date actually has a lot of complexity to it,
容易,但没有,日期实际上有很大的复杂性,
because of all the different ways we represent dates in
因为我们代表日期的不同方式
the world, Same, similar to strings complexity, And
世界,相同,类似于字符串复杂性和
then there's data, D-A-T-A, that represents a bag o' bits,
D-A-T-A还有数据,代表一个袋的位,
Just a bits, bunch of bits in there, Usually this might be
只是一个碎片,堆位,通常这种可能
something like an image, the bits of an image, or
像一个图像,图像的位,或
something like that, Something you get over the the network,
这样,在网络,
So data is how we represent those,
所以数据是如何表示这些,
Notice that there is a struct, it's a value type,
请注意,有一个结构体,这是一个值类型,
It gets passed around copy on right, And
它被传递正确的复制,和
you'll start seeing data in UI maybe week five or
你会开始看到数据的UI可能星期5到
six of this class, All right, initialization,
6这个类的,初始化,
So initialization is very complicated, You're
所以初始化是非常复杂的,你
gonna have to read the reading assignment on it eventually,
要读它最终的阅读作业,
I'm gonna give you the really fast highlights of it, init
我要给你一个非常快的,init
method, again, we can have them on classes or structs,
方法,再一次,我们可以在类或结构,
They are used to initialize any of the properties that we
他们是用来初始化我们的任何属性
didn't initialize with equals or using lazy or they were
没有初始化与等于或使用懒惰或他们
optionals, All those are taken care of and if there's one
可选,所有这些照顾,如果有一个
left, or more than one left, then we need an initializer,
离开,或一个以上的离开,然后我们需要一个初始化,
To initialize it, And they're kind of a pain in the neck,
对它进行初始化,他们讨厌的家伙,
Because, especially for classes, For structs,
因为,特别是对于类,结构体,
they're not a pain in the neck, They are perfectly fine,
他们不是一个脖子疼痛,非常好,
Struct, you just have an init with whatever argue you want,
结构,你就有一个init任何认为你想要的,
arguments you want, And initialize your variables,
你想要的参数,并初始化变量,
It's all very simple, But for classes, it's a little more
这都是非常简单的,但是对于类,多一点
complicated, Now, whether you're a struct or a class,
复杂,现在,不管你是一个结构或一个类,
you can have multiple init, And they can have different
可以有多个init,他们可以有不同的
arguments, As long as you give them enough arguments to be
参数,只要给他们足够的论据
able to initialize all their variables, you're good to go,
能初始化所有的变量,你很棒,
So you can have as many inits as you want,
所以你可以有你想要尽可能多的init,
And a lot of classes have multiple inits, Meaning on
和很多类有多个init,意义
kinda how they are being used, how they are being created,
它们是如何被使用的,他们是如何被创造出来,
Think of something like string,
想到类似的字符串,
String has an init that takes a double,
字符串有一个init,双,
It has a string that takes another sting if you want to
它有一个字符串,另一个刺痛,如果你想
make a copy of the string it turns out, It takes an init,
原来的字符串的副本,需要一个初始化,
It has all these things that you can compare to string,
所有这些事情,你可以比较字符串,
Or not all the things you compare string but
或者不是所有的事情但是你比较字符串
a lot of things you can compare to a string,
很多东西你可以比较一个字符串,
It has an initialized that it will take that as an argument
它有一个初始化,它将作为参数
for example, Callers execute your init by creating
例如,调用者从创造执行init
one of the thing, They just put the name of the type and
的一个东西,他们只是把类型和名称
parentheses and the arguments you want for that init, So
括号和你想要的参数初始化,所以
they pick which of your init that they want and
他们选择你的init,他们想要
they call that one with those arguments,
他们称之为一个与这些参数,
We've seen many examples of this in our lecture, so far,
我们看到许多这样的例子在我们的讲座,到目前为止,
You get some inits for free, If you're a base class, okay,
你得到一些init免费,如果你是一个基类,好吧,
you don't inherit from anything else,
你不继承什么,
You get a free init with no arguments, Congratulations,
你得到一个免费的init没有参数,祝贺你,
So that means, at least, people can create you,
这意味着,至少人们可以创造你,
But, again, if you have any vars that aren't initialized,
但是,如果你有任何增值供应商没有初始化,
you're gonna have to create your inits that initialize
你必须创建你的init初始化
them, Structs are even better, They get an init that has all
,结构更好,他们得到一个初始化所有
of their vars, Now if a struct implements even one of its own
var,现在即使结构实现一个自己的
initializers, it stops getting this one, this free one,
初始化,它停止这个,这个免费,
You only get the free one if you don't do any other ones,
只有免费的如果你不做任何其他的,
So it's like the default one,
就像默认,
And we saw this in the lecture also,
我们看到了这个讲座,
We got the free one in the init function, first operand,
我们得到了免费的init函数,第一个操作数,
We never wrote that init function, we got it for free,
我们从不写道,init函数,我们免费得到它,
It just appeared and we were able to call it, , so
它就出现了,我们可以叫它,,所以
structure nice you get the basic free init for
结构很好的得到基本免费init
all your vars, What can you do inside of a nit? I'm
你所有的var,你能做什么在一个没用的人吗?
gonna start going fast here, okay, So here we go, One,
要开始快,好,我们走,,
you can set any properties value even if that property
即使这属性可以设置任何属性值
already had its value set, you can reset something else,
已经有了它的价值,你可以重置,
You can set lets, So you're gonna have a let that's
你可以设置允许,所以你会有一个让
got less x equal 5, You can still reset it in your init,
少x = 5,您仍然可以重置你的初始化,
Your init is allowed to set lets, You can call other init
允许你的初始化设置允许,你可以调用其他初始化
methods okay in your own class or your own struct, And you do
方法在类或自己的结构,和你
that by saying self,init with whatever the arguments to that
说自我,初始化的参数
init method are so init methods can call each other,
init方法可以相互调用init方法,
In a class, you can call super,init,
在一个类中,您可以调用super,初始化,
An initializer from your super class,
从超类初始化器,
Of course you need to get your super class initialized,
当然你需要超类初始化时,
Now, when we start talking about class though,
现在,当我们开始讨论类,
and we start talking about calling inits in our super,
我们开始讨论在我们的超级调用init,
and we start thinking about inheritance,
我们开始考虑继承,
it gets really complicated, So
它变得非常复杂,所以
let's start thinking about class and break this down,
让我们开始思考类和分解,
Let's start with what are you required to do in an init for
让我们从你开始需要做在一个init
a class? in a struct it's easy you're just required to
一个类?
initialize all your vars that aren't initialized, But
初始化所有的var没有初始化,但是
in a class what are you required to do? By the time
在课堂上你必须做什么?
it's done you have to have initialized all your vars,
做你需要初始化所有的增值,
We know that, There are two types of initializers,
我们知道,有两种类型的初始化,
A convenience initializer,
一个方便的初始化,
This is only for classes, A convenience initializer and
这只是为类,方便初始值设定项
what's called a designated initializer,
所谓的指定初始化,
Designated is the default, There's no keyword it's just
指定的是默认的,没有字的
if it's not marked convenience then it's a designated,
如果不方便那就指定,
Now here's where the rules come in,
现在这里的规则,
A designated initializer non convenience must and
指定的初始化必须和不方便
can only, call the designated initializer that it is in,
只能,调用指定初始化,
that is in it's immediate superclass,
在直接超类,
it's very important, It has to call a superclass init
这是非常重要的,它必须调用超类的init
and it has to get designated initializer, It cannot call
它指定初始化,不能打电话
it's convenience initializer in a superclass, Nor
它是方便在超类初始化器,也没有
can it call two classes up the inherent chain unless the one
可以打电话给两个类的连锁,除非一个
right above inherited the init from the one up above, and
正上方继承了init从上面的一个
we'll talk about that in a second, You have to initialize
我们会讲到,你必须初始化
all of your properties before you call that super init,
你所有的属性称之为超级初始化之前,
You must have completely
你必须完全
done all the ones that you introduced in your class,
完成了所有那些你在类,介绍
Get them initialized before you call super init, And,
让他们在你调用super init初始化,而且,
you have to call the super one before you can reinitialize or
你必须叫超级才能重新启动或
change the value of any of it's Properties, obviously,
改变它的任何属性的值,显然,
you gotta let your super class have a chance to initialize
你必须让你的超类有一个初始化的机会
itself before you start mucking with its properties,
与它的属性本身在你开始清理,
Otherwise, when units call super, it's probably gonna
否则,当调用super单位,它可能会
blast whatever you did to its properties,
不管你对它的属性,
A convenience init can only, must and can only,
方便init只能,必须只能,
call an initializer in its own class, no super,
调用一个初始化的类,不超,
Only in your own class,
只有在你自己的类,
convenience initializer only in your own class, You can
方便只在自己的类初始化器,你可以
call it another convenience or you can call it designator,
叫它另一个便利或者你可以称之为指示器,
but it has to be in your own class,
但它必须是在你自己的类,
not in your super class, And
不是在你的超类,
a convenience init has to call whatever init it's gonna call
一个方便init调用init它会叫
in itself before it can set any of the property
本身才能设置的任何属性
values, It's kind of different from an init that calls into
值,这是一种不同于一个调用init
super because that one has to do its initialization,
超,因为它是一个初始化,
the designated one, before it calls super,
指定一个,超级之前调用,
This, in this case, you have to do convenience,
这一点,在这种情况下,你要做的方便,
you have to call your other one first,
你必须打电话给你其他的一分之一,
And the calling of all other inits, whatever you do, any
和其他所有的调用init,无论你做什么,
inits that you have to call has to be done in all cases,
init,你必须调用必须在所有情况下,
before you start calling methods on yourself or
在你开始在自己或调用方法
accessing properties,
访问属性,
Not setting the properties, but accessing them,
不设置属性,但访问他们,
In other words, you have to be fully initialized before your
换句话说,你必须完全初始化之前
init can start using your class, All right,
初始化可以开始使用您的类,
whew is right: a lot of rules there, and a lot of them
呼是对的:很多规则,很多
are conflicting and all that stuff, Let's make it even more
是相互矛盾的,所有的东西,让它更
complicated when we talk about inheriting inits, So,
当我们讨论继承init复杂,所以,
you wanna get some inits from your super class,
你想要得到一些从你的超类初始化,
whoa, not so fast, If you don't implement
哇,没那么快,如果你不实现
any designated inits, you only implement convenience inits,
指定init,您只有实现方便init,
then you'll inherit all of your super classes designated,
然后你将继承所有指定父类,
but only if you don't implement any of them,
但只有如果你不实现任何,
And if you implement even one designated init,
甚至如果你实现一个指定的初始化,
now you're not gonna inherit all your super classes, If you
现在你不是要继承超类,如果你
override all of your super classes designated inits,
覆盖你所有的超类指定init,
then you'll inherit all of its con, convenience inits,
然后你将继承所有的案子,方便init,
Now why is that? That's because your superclass,
现在,这是为什么呢?
when it implements these convenience inits,
当它实现了这些便利init,
it depends on the designated inits being implemented,
这取决于指定init实施,
so you have to implement them all,
所以你必须实现它们,
Of course, you could inherit them all by implementing
当然,你可以通过实现继承它们
none of them as well, So, any init that you inherit by these
他们都没有,所以,任何init承受这些
rules can be used to satisfy any of these other,
规则可以用来满足这些,
other requirements that we're talking about on the previous
其他需求,我们先前的讨论
stage, You can make an init required, You just say
阶段,你可以使一个init必需的,你只是说
required init, Required is a key word, and that will
需要初始化,需要的是一个关键词,会的
make it so the subclass has to implement that init, okay,
使它的子类必须实现init,好吧,
it's required, Failable inits, we talked about these with
这是必需的,Failable init,我们谈论这些
double, If you put a question mark after your init,
翻倍,如果你把一个问号你初始化后,
init question mark, that means that this init can fail,
init问号,这意味着这个初始化失败,
And that means that this init, or when you create this thing,
这意味着这个init,或者当您创建这个东西,
will return optional version of this class, So
将返回这类的可选版本,所以呢
we thought it was double,
我们认为这是翻倍,
If we said double parentheses string, it would return
如果我们说双括号字符串,它将返回
an optional double, It was a failable init, and
一个可选的两倍,这是一个failable init,和
that's because you could have said double of hello, and
那是因为你有双说你好,和
you would be like " I can't turn it into double: fail",
你就像“我不能把它变成双:失败”,
And the way you fail out of a failable init is you just
你失败了你只是failable init
return nil, Otherwise,
返回nil,否则,
you don't return anything out of init, it just initializes,
你不返回任何初始化,初始化,
but the one time you return anything is out
但一次你返回任何值
a failed init, you can return nil, So, an example here is
初始化失败,你可以返回nil,所以,这是一个例子
UIImage, UIImaged named looks up that image in
用户界面图像,名为查找的用户界面图像,图像
the xe assets, Remember that xe assets thing that I moved
xe资产,记住xe资产我感动
off to supporting files at the beginning of the first demo?
去支持文件的开头第一个演示?
This looks it up in there, of course, it might not find it,
这看起来在那里,当然,它可能不会找到它,
So we do if let image = UIImage(named: "foo"),
所以我们如果让图像=用户界面图像(命名为:“foo”),
then we do something, otherwise we fail,
然后我们做点什么,否则我们失败了,
that UI image initializer failed, Alright, Any and
UI图像初始化失败,任何
AnyObject, There is no more init, we're done with init,
AnyObject,没有更多的init,我们完成了初始化,
Any and AnyObject: these are types, special types,
任何AnyObject:这些类型,特殊类型,
These types really are almost exclusively used for backwards
这些类型是几乎完全用于向后
compatibility with Objective C because Objective C had a type
兼容Objective - C因为Objective - C类型
in it called id, which was kind of like Any,
它被称为id,有点像任何,
AnyObject actually, So Swift needed some compatibility, but
AnyObject实际上,所以迅速需要一些兼容性,但是
Swift doesn't really use Any very much, so
斯威夫特没有使用任何,所以
we wouldn't, Swift is strongly typed, So you wouldn't wanna
我们不会,斯威夫特是强类型的,所以你不会想
have a type which is like, it can be anything, Okay, because
有一个类型,它可以是任何东西,好吧,因为
that's what Any and AnyObject are, it's like anything,
这是任何和AnyObject,就像任何东西,
any type, It's this weird kind of typeless type kinda thing,
任何类型,它的这种奇怪的无类型类型有点事情,
The only difference between Any and
任何的唯一区别
AnyObject is AnyObject can only be a class,
AnyObject AnyObject只能是一个类,
it has be a reference type, Any can be anything,
它是一个引用类型,可以是任何东西,
reference or a value type, that's the only difference,
引用或值类型,这是唯一的区别,
So why do we have these AnyObject things?
为什么我们有这些AnyObject东西?
Where are they gonna show up? Well,
它们会出现在哪里?
there are some methods in iOS where one of the arguments
有些方法在iOS的一个参数
truly could be anything, One example here is when you have
真正的可以是任何东西,这是当你有一个很好的例子
multiple MVCs, which we're gonna learn about next week,
多个mvc,下周我们要了解,
The way you go from one to the next, next is called segueing,
你从一个到另一个,下一个叫做segue,
you segue from one MVC to the next,
你从一个MVC segue,
And the thing that causes a segue to happen, okay,
导致一个segue发生的事情,好的,
is the argument in this method called prepare for
是这个方法的参数叫准备
segue called sender, okay,
segue称为发送者,
just like we had sender in the IB action, So
就像发送方的IB行动,
the sender is the one who's causing this segue to happen,
发件人是谁造成这个segue发生,
well, a button could be causing a segue to happen,
嗯,一个按钮可以导致一个segue发生,
a line in a table view could be causing it, Some custom
一条线在一个表格视图可以使其,一些自定义
piece of code of yours could be causing this MVC to segue,
你的代码会造成上述MVC segue,
So when you're preparing for it, you've gotta be
所以当你准备,你要
able to say which one it was, and that's just Any, So
能说哪一个,这是任何,所以
if this were a Swift API, they wouldn't have done Any,
如果这是一个迅速API,他们不会做这些事了,
They'd have had a protocol where you could be a segue
他们会有一个协议,你可以继续
sender, And you'd have to implement probably some
发送者,你可能会实现一些
functionality that would make sense here, But in this case,
功能,有意义,但是在这种情况下,
it's Any, It knows optional Any too because you can have
任何,它知道可选任何因为你可以
nil, the center could be nil, Where else will you see it?
nil,中心可能是零,其他的你看到了吗?
You could have an array of AnyObject or an array of Any,
你可以有一个AnyObject或数组的数组,
That could be an array that has doubles and strings and
这可能是双打和字符串和数组
things mixed in there, Now you might be tempted to use this
事情复杂,现在你可能会想用这个
in your assignment number two when you see the assignment,
在作业2号当你看到作业,
But you're not allowed to
但你不可以
because one of the required tasks says you can't use Any
因为说你不能使用任何所需的任务
or AnyObject, Also you wouldn't be very Swifty,
或AnyObject,你也不会很中高阶层,
In Swift, if we wanted to put doubles and
在迅速,如果我们想把双打
strings in the same array, we use an enum,
字符串在同一个数组,我们使用enum,
That's what we did with our operations array, and that's
这是我们所做的与我们的操作数组,这就是
what we would do in Swift, so we wouldn't use AnyObject,
在斯威夫特我们要做的,所以我们不会使用AnyObject,
Another thing you could possibly use Any for is for
你可以使用任何的另一件事是
a cookie, right, some piece of data that you're giving
一块饼干,你给的数据
out that you don't want people to know what class it is,
你不希望人们知道它是什么类,
And they're just gonna give it back to you at some point,
他们会还给你,
and you'll do something with it and
与,,你会做些什么
only you know what it is,
只有你知道它是什么,
So you know, an opaque type, you could use it for
所以你知道,一个不透明的类型,你可以用它来
that, How do we use something of type Any, because we can't
,我们如何使用任何类型的东西,因为我们不能
send any messages to it cuz it's not of AnyType, so
发送任何消息,因为这不是AnyType的
we don't know any methods that it does or whatever, Instead,
我们不知道它或者其他任何方法,相反,
we have convert it, and we convert type Any or, or
我们已经把它,我们将任何或类型,或
AnyObject into some class that we know about using as,
AnyObject一些类,我们知道使用,
As is a key word, and we do as question mark because we don't
是一个关键词,我们因为我们不做问号
know for sure that we can convert something,
我们可以把一些肯定,
so it's an optional, And we use it with if let,
这是一个可选的,我们如果我们使用它,
So if I had some variable unknown,
如果我有一些未知变量,
which is of type Any, so I don't really know what it is,
这是任何类型的,所以我真的不知道那是什么,
But I think it might be MyType, I'm not sure,
但我认为这可能是MyType,我不确定,
But I think that might be MyType in there, So I say,
但我认为可能MyType,所以我说,
if let foo = unknown as MyType,
如果让foo = MyType未知,
if let, Then inside there, foo is now going to be unknown,
如果让,那里面,foo现在是未知的,
but as MyType, So I will be able to
但随着MyType,所以我可以
send foo message whatever my tape, I'll be able to send foo
发送foo消息不管我的磁带,我可以发送foo
whatever MyType understands, methods and vars,
无论MyType理解、方法和增值
So that's how we use it, We use this "as?", it's called
这是我们如何使用它,我们使用这种“一样?
casting, This casting, by the way, not just for AnyObject,
铸造,铸造,顺便说一下,不仅对AnyObject,
we can cast other things, For example, if I had a variable
我们可以把其他事情,例如,如果我有一个变量
which is, vc which is a type UIViewController,
风险投资是一种界面控制器,
I could assign it to UI, to CalculatorViewController,
我可以将它分配给UI,CalculatorViewController,
Because CalculatorViewController is
因为CalculatorViewController
a subclass of UIViewController, So
ui的一个子类
it is a UIViewController, so I could assign it to vc, But
这是一个ui,所以我可以将它分配给风投,但是
if I assign it like this, with this typing,
如果我这样分配,用这个打字,
I cannot say vc,displayValue cuz vc,displayValue,
我不能说vc,displayValue因为vc,displayValue,
displayValue is a var in CalculatorViewController,
displayValue是var CalculatorViewController,
and vc is of type UIViewController,
和vc界面控制器类型,
Even though it points to a CalculatorViewController,
即使它指向CalculatorViewController,
from Swift's perspective, it's typed as vc, and
从斯威夫特的角度看,它的类型的vc,
Swift is strongly typed, So if I wanted to send displayValue,
斯威夫特是强类型的,如果我想发送displayValue,
I would have to say, if I can let calcVC = vc
我不得不说,如果我能让calcVC = vc
as a CalculatorViewController Now I can send displayValue to
我可以发送displayValue CalculatorViewController现在
calcVC, Cuz it's the type that you actually
calcVC,因为这是你真正的类型
type it as that matters, not what it's pointing to, So you
类型是重要的,而不是指向,所以你
have to use as to get it to be something that you really
需要使用它,你真的吗
wanna use, Okay, I'm gonna go a little bit over here,
想用,好吧,我要在这里,一点
If you have to go, it's, it's fine, just keep it quiet,
如果你要去,,它很好,只是保持安静,
The last thing I'm gonna talk about is user defaults,
我要讲的最后一件事就是用户违约,
User defaults is a very lightweight,
用户默认设置是一个非常轻量级的,
limited database, It's a tiny little database that persists
有限的数据库,它是一个小的数据库仍然存在
between launchings of your app, It's great for
发射之间的应用程序,它是伟大的
things like settings and stuff like that,
比如设置之类的,
Don't put anything big in there, The only thing you can
不要把任何东西大,唯一你可以
put in this database is what's called a property list,
在这个数据库是所谓的属性列表,
A property list just means any combination of array,
一个属性列表就意味着数组的任意组合,
dictionary, string, date, data, or
字典,字符串,日期,数据,或者
a number, like int, float, double, whatever,
一个数字,如int、浮点数、翻倍,无论如何,
That's what a property list is, It's just conceptual,
这就是一个属性列表,只是概念上的,
There's no actual type property list, unfortunately,
没有实际的类型属性列表,不幸的是,
If this were a Swift API, it probably would be such a type,
如果这是一个迅速API,它可能会是这样一个类型,
It could be a protocol, But anyway, there's not,
它可能是一个协议,但无论如何,没有,
This is from Objective-C, So since there's no type
这是来自objective - c,既然没有类型
that represents that codgepodge of classes,
代表codgepodge类,
this API that I'm gonna show user defaults uses Any, And
这个API,我要显示用户使用任何违约,和
this is what it looks like, It has this core, set, and
这就是它的样子,它有这样一个核心,集,和
get, Set Any? Now that Any can't really be Any,
获取、设置吗?
it has to be one of those types, string, dictionary,
它必须是其中的一个类型,字符串,字典,
array, whatever, it has to be be a Property List,
数组,不管怎样,它必须是一个属性列表,
forKey string, So you just put it, anything you want
forKey字符串,所以你把它,任何你想要的
in this database under a certain key,
在这个数据库某个键,
And then you get it back out by saying, object for key, and
然后你把它弄回来说,为主要对象,
it returns you an Any, And it's an optional Any because
它返回你的任何,这是一个可选的任何原因
it might not be in the database,
它可能不是在数据库中,
in which it is returned nil, So it says any but
它返回nil,所以说任何但
it's not really Any, it's Any as long as the property lists,
它不是任何,只要属性列表,
which means it's one of these ten classes or
这意味着它的其中一个十类或吗
whatever, The way you read and
无论如何,你的阅读和方式
write it, you don't create a user default by saying let
写,你不创建一个用户说我们违约
x equal user defaults with parentheses,
x =用户违约与括号,
You say let defaults = UserDefaults,standard, so
你说我们违约= UserDefaults标准,所以
that's a type var on the user default struct,
这是一个var用户默认的结构类型,
And you get this standard UserDefaults and
你得到这个标准UserDefaults和
then you can send it things like set,
然后你可以把它设置,
that thing I was telling you, set Any, And here,
那件事我告诉你,任何,在这里,
I've got three different sets, one of them setting of double,
我有三个不同的集合,其中的一个设置双,
one setting an array of ints, An array of ints is okay
一个设置一个整数数组,数组的整数没问题
because array is part of property list, And so is int,
因为数组属性列表的一部分,因此是int,
so that's okay, That's a property list, An array
这是好的,这是一个属性列表,一个数组
of ints is a property list, a property list, So is a double,
int属性列表,一个属性列表,所以是一个双,
cuz it's one of those types, And I just set them in there,
因为它是其中的一个类型,我只是让他们,
And then when I get them out, I use that object for key,
当我把它们弄出来,我使用该对象的键,
And actually for some common types,
实际上,对于一些常见的类型,
like doubles, arrays and dictionaries, there's actually
像双打,数组和字典,实际上
a nice little method in there to give you that type back,
一个方法给你回信息,
That's so you that don't get an Any back and
所以你不得到一个回去
then have to do as, Because you know that objects for
然后要做,因为你知道对象
key returns an Any until you give this Any and
键返回一个任何直到你给这个
you have to go if this thing has a double,
你如果这个东西有双,
then I've got it, That would be annoying, So instead,
我懂了,烦人,所以,
it just has a method called double that does that as for
它有一个方法叫做这两倍
you, And if the as fails then you, I think either,
你,如果是失败那么你,我认为,
I don't know if it returns a double or an optional double,
我不知道如果它返回一个双重或一个可选的两倍,
but you might get zero back, you might get a nil,
但是你可能会拿回零,你可能会得到一个零,
I don't remember exactly, But for array in dictionary,
我完全不记得了,但是在字典数组,
a couple of interesting things to note, Obviously,
有趣的东西要注意,显然,
the Anys that are inside the array in dictionary,
在数组的任何字典,
those will have to be property lists as well, the things that
这些必须属性列表,的事情
are returned to you, And also know that dictionary,
返回给你,也知道,字典,
this convenience method dictionary,
这个便利方法字典,
it's the string is always the key in the dictionary,
它的字符串总是在字典里的关键
If you had a dictionary where the keys were say, ints,
如果你有一本字典的钥匙在哪里说,整数,
I think that's a valid key, yeah, in the dictionary, yeah,
我认为这是一个有效的关键,是的,在字典里,是的,
it is, Then you would not use this convenience method,
是,那么你不会使用这个方便的方法,
You'd have to use object for key and then use as to turn it
你必须使用对象为关键,然后使用,把它
back into a dictionary with int keys,
回一个字典,int钥匙,
Saving the database is autosave, so you actually
保存数据库自动保存,所以你真的
don't have to save it, If you wanna force it to save because
不需要保存它,如果你想拯救因为力量
you're worried that the autosave might not happen,
你担心autosave可能不会发生,
You're gonna exit your program or something, you can use this
你要退出程序,您可以使用这个
method synchronize, It's called synchronize defaults,
方法同步,它叫做同步违约,
It will synchronize it, That's almost it, assertions,
它将同步,这几乎是它,断言,
Sorry, one last quick thing, Assertions are just a little
对不起,最后一个快速,断言只是一点点
Swift function that takes a closure as the first argument
斯威夫特函数接受一个闭包作为第一个参数
and a message as the second argument,
和消息作为第二个参数,
All it does is it executes the closure, If that returns true,
所有它执行关闭,如果返回true,
it does not crash your program, If it returns false,
它不会崩溃你的程序,如果它返回false,
it crashes your program and prints that message out, So
程序崩溃并打印信息,
you could put, you know, some validation call, This line of
你知道,你可以把一些验证电话,这行
code will not even execute in the version of your app that
代码将不执行的应用程序版本
you ship on the app store, When you build the app for
你船在app store,构建应用程序
release, the asserts are completely ignored,
释放,断言是完全忽视,
It doesn't even actually give the closure, let alone crash,
实际上它甚至不给关闭,更不用说崩溃,
It just ignores them, so this is a debugging thing only,
只是忽略了他们,所以这是一个调试的事情,
okay? That's it! For Friday,
好吧?
we do have Friday session, it's at the normal time, And
我们周五的会议,它是在正常的时间,
it's gonna be on source code management,
它会在源代码管理,
A really cool way to manage your code even if you're just
一个很酷的方式来管理您的代码,即使你只是
one programmer working on a project by yourself, And then
一个程序员在一个项目,然后
next week I'm going to talk about doing custom drawing
下周我要讲做自定义绘图
in your own view, Multi-touch, like pinches and swipes, and
在自己看来,多点触控,喜欢捏和啤酒,
things like that, And finally, multiple MVCs so
类似这样的事情,最后,多个mvc
we can build a more powerful calculator,
我们可以建立一个更强大的计算器,
Your assignment two has gone out, It's already posted,
作业两个出去,它已经发布,
It's essentially enhancing your calculator with a lot of
它本质上是加强计算器的
the things that I talked about today like tuples and
我今天像元组和谈论
defaulting values and even value types,
默认值甚至是值类型,
All kinds of stuff, So we'll have a lot of fun with that,
各种各样的东西,所以我们会有很多的乐趣,
>> For more,
更多> >,
please visit us at standford,edu
请访问我们在斯坦福,埃杜